<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-04-06T16:03:04+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Mi nuevo pok</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Map</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/map/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Map" /><published>2023-03-10T15:56:47+01:00</published><updated>2023-03-10T15:56:47+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/map</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/map/"><![CDATA[<script src="/assets/js/leaflet-providers.js"></script>

<p>Quick Access: RWTH Aachen University. Universität Bremen. TU Chemnitz. Clausthal University of Technology. TU Darmstadt. Technische Universität Dresden. University of Duisburg-Essen. Universität Hamburg</p>

<link rel="stylesheet" href="/assets/css/leaflet.css" />

<script src="/assets/js/leaflet.js"></script>

<div id="map" style="height: 400px;"></div>

<script src="/assets/js/map.js"></script>

<h2 id="rwth-aachen-university">RWTH Aachen University</h2>
<p>Media Computing Group
Jan Borchers – hci.rwth-aachen.de</p>

<p>At the Media Computing Group, headed by Prof. Dr. Jan Borchers, we work in Human-Computer Interaction. We develop and study new interaction theories, techniques, and systems in areas like personal digital fabrication and personal design, tangible, mobile, and wearable user interfaces, interactive textiles, multitouch tables and interactive surfaces, augmented reality, and visual coding environments. Our goal is to make the Brave New World of interactive technologies useful by making it usable. Since starting in October 2003, we have become one of Germany’s best-published research groups at CHI, the premier international academic conference in the field.</p>

<h2 id="universität-bremen">Universität Bremen</h2>

<p>Digital Media Lab, TZI
Rainer Malaka – tzi.de</p>

<p>CGVR, TZI
Gabriel Zachmann – tzi.de</p>

<p>The Center for Computing Technologies (TZI) at the University of Bremen conducts research at the core of a massive societal trend: The digital revolution, which affects all areas of our lives. Important research questions include: What kind of technologies will we have in 10 to 20 years? How can we make sure that they will be safe, dependable, and beneficial for society? And most of all: How can technology serve humans–instead of replacing them? TZI has conducted research in these areas since its foundation in 1995, working on approximately 120 projects per year. One main goal is to transfer results from basic research to industry as quickly as possible in order to generate the greatest benefits for society.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Quick Access: RWTH Aachen University. Universität Bremen. TU Chemnitz. Clausthal University of Technology. TU Darmstadt. Technische Universität Dresden. University of Duisburg-Essen. Universität Hamburg]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">References 2022</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="References 2022" /><published>2023-03-01T15:56:47+01:00</published><updated>2023-03-01T15:56:47+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/"><![CDATA[<ol class="bibliography"><li><span id="henning2022standing">of Technology), A. H. (K. I., of Bamberg), F. N. (U., of Technology), A. P. (K. I., of Bamberg), D. H. (U., &amp; of Technology), P. M. (K. I. (2022, May 1). <i>Standing out among the daily spam: How to catch website owners’ attention by means of vulnerability notifications</i>. https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519847</span></li>
<li><span id="Lagner2022EyeMeet">(KIT), M. L., (KIT), P. T., &amp; (KIT), A. M. (2022, May 1). <i>EyeMeet: A Joint Attention Support System for Remote Meetings</i>. https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519792</span></li>
<li><span id="Ruoff2022onyx">(KIT), M. R., (CMU), B. M., &amp; (KIT), A. M. (2022, May 1). <i>ONYX - User Interfaces for Assisting in Interactive Task Learning for Natural Language Interfaces of Data Visualization Tools</i>. https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519793</span></li>
<li><span id="2022NittalaStepsOnSkinDevices">University), A. S. N. (S., &amp; University), J. S. (S. (2022, April 30). <i>Next Steps in Epidermal Computing: Opportunities and Challenges for Soft On-Skin Devices</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3517668</span></li>
<li><span id="2022GuentherSmooth">Darmstadt), S. G. (T. U., München), J. R. (L. M. U., Darmstadt), D. S. (T. U., München), F. M. (L. M. U., Darmstadt), M. S. (T. U., Darmstadt), J. R. (T. U., Darmstadt), A. M. (T. U., &amp; München), M. M. (L. M. U. (2022, April 30). <i>Smooth as Steel Wool: Effects of Visual Stimuli on the Haptic Perception of Roughness in Virtual Reality</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3517454</span></li>
<li><span id="2022MuenderOrganTangibles">Thomas Muender (Digital Media Lab, U. of B., Anke Reinschluessel (Digital Media Lab, U. of B., Daniela Salzmann (University Hospital for Visceral Surgery, P. I. U. S.-H., Carl von Ossietzky University of Oldenburg, (cirp GmbH), T. L., for Digital Medicine MEVIS), A. S. (F. I., Dirk Weyhe (University Hospital for Visceral Surgery, P. I. U. S.-H., Carl von Ossietzky University of Oldenburg, Tanja Döring (Digital Media Lab, U. of B., &amp; Rainer Malaka (Digital Media Lab, U. of B. (2022, April 30). <i>Evaluating Soft Organ-Shaped Tangibles for Medical Virtual Reality</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519715</span></li>
<li><span id="2022LuoPlacement"><i>Where Should We Put It? Layout and Placement Strategies of Documents in Augmented Reality for Collaborative Sensemaking</i>. (2022, April 30). https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3501946</span></li>
<li><span id="2022MarkyVoting"><i>Investigating Usability and User Experience of Individually Verifiable Internet Voting Schemes</i>. (2022, April 30). https://doi.org/10.1145/3459604</span></li>
<li><span id="2022ParkFoolProofJoint">Keunwoo Park (Hasso Plattner Institute, G., Potsdam, Conrad Lempert (Hasso Plattner Institute, G., Potsdam, Muhammad Abdullah (Hasso Plattner Institute, G., Potsdam, Shohei Katakura (Hasso Plattner Institute, G., Potsdam, Jotaro Shigeyama (Hasso Plattner Institute, G., Potsdam, Thijs Roumen (Hasso Plattner Institute, G., Potsdam, &amp; Patrick Baudisch (Hasso Plattner Institute, G., Potsdam. (2022, April 30). <i>FoolProofJoint: Reducing Assembly Errors of Laser Cut 3D Models by Means of Custom Joint Patterns</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3501919</span></li>
<li><span id="2022EngertStraide">Dresden), S. E. (T. U., Dresden), K. K. (T. U., Dresden), A. P. (T. U., &amp; Dresden), R. D. (T. U. (2022, April 30). <i>STRAIDE: A Research Platform for Shape-Changing Spatial Displays based on Actuated Strings</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3517462</span></li>
<li><span id="2022WindlAutomating">Munich), M. W. (L. M. U., of Regensburg), N. H. (U., Munich), A. S. (L. M. U., &amp; Munich), S. S. F. (L. M. U. (2022, April 30). <i>Automating Contextual Privacy Policies: Design and Evaluation of a Production Tool for Digital Consumer Privacy Awareness</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3517688</span></li>
<li><span id="2022WindlDiscovery">Munich), M. W. (L. M. U., Munich), S. S. F. (L. M. U., University), L. Z. (U., Munich), A. S. (L. M. U., &amp; of Technology), P. W. W. (C. U. (2022, April 30). <i>It Is Not Always Discovery Time: Four Pragmatic Approaches in Designing AI Systems</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3501943</span></li>
<li><span id="2022DreyCollaborative">Tobias Drey (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., Patrick Albus (Institute of Psychology + Education, U. U., Simon der Kinderen (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., Maximilian Milo (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., Thilo Segschneider (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., Linda Chanzab (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., Michael Rietzler (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., Tina Seufert (Institute of Psychology + Education, U. U., &amp; Enrico Rukzio (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U. (2022, April 30). <i>Towards Collaborative Learning in Virtual Reality: A Comparison of Co-Located Symmetric and Asymmetric Pair-Learning</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3517641</span></li>
<li><span id="2022AbdrabouPasswordReuse">Yasmeen Abdrabou (Bundeswehr University Munich, U. of G., Munich), J. S. (B. U., Egypt), A. S. (F. L. L. C., Ken Pfeuffer (Aarhus University, B. U. M., of Bayreuth), D. B. (U., of Glasgow), M. K. (U., &amp; Munich), F. A. (B. U. (2022, April 30). <i>"Your Eyes Tell You Have Used This Password Before": Identifying Password Reuse from Gaze and Keystroke Dynamics</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3517531</span></li>
<li><span id="2022PrangeWhere">Sarah Prange (University of the Bundeswehr Munich, L. M. U. M., of the Bundeswehr Munich), S. D. R. (U., Munich), T. D. (L. M. U., &amp; of the Bundeswehr Munich), F. A. (U. (2022, April 30). <i>"Where did you first meet the owner?” – Exploring Usable Authentication for Smart Home Visitors</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519777</span></li>
<li><span id="2022VolkPriCheck">Munich), V. V. (L. M. U., Sarah Prange (University of the Bundeswehr Munich, L. M. U. M., &amp; of the Bundeswehr Munich), F. A. (U. (2022, April 30). <i>PriCheck - An Online Assistant for Smart Device Purchases</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519827</span></li>
<li><span id="2022SpielADHD">Katta Spiel (Human-Computer Interaction Group, T. U. W., Weimar), E. H. (B.-U., of Florida), R. M. W. (U., &amp; of Sussex), J. G. (U. (2022, April 30). <i>ADHD and Technology Research – Investigated by Neurodivergent Readers</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445196</span></li>
<li><span id="2022MarchettiPetRobot"><i>Pet-Robot or Appliance? Care Home Residents with Dementia Respond to a Zoomorphic Floor Washing Robot</i>. (2022, April 30). https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3517463</span></li>
<li><span id="2022StemasovShapeFindAR">Evgeny Stemasov (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., Tobias Wagner (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., Jan Gugenheimer (Télécom Paris - LTCI, I. P. de P., &amp; Enrico Rukzio (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U. (2022, April 30). <i>ShapeFindAR: Exploring In-Situ Spatial Search for Physical Artifact Retrieval using Mixed Reality </i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3517682</span></li>
<li><span id="2022LiBalancing">Munich), J. L. (L. M. U., Munich), F. F. (L. M. U., Group), S. C. (B. M. W., &amp; Munich), A. B. (L. M. U. (2022, April 30). <i>Towards Balancing Real-World Awareness and VR Immersion in Mobile VR</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519824</span></li>
<li><span id="2022CalepsocARdLearner">of Stuttgart), A. S. C. (U., of Stuttgart), N. H. (U., of Stuttgart), N. B. S. (U., of Stuttgart), V. B. (U., &amp; of Stuttgart), M. S. (U. (2022, April 30). <i>cARdLearner: Using Expressive Virtual Agents when Learning Vocabulary in Augmented Reality</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519631</span></li>
<li><span id="2022HubeAvatars">Natalie Hube (Mercedes-Benz AG, U. of S., Kresimir Vidackovic (Hochschule der Medien, U. of A. S., &amp; of Stuttgart), M. S. (U. (2022, April 30). <i>Using Expressive Avatars to Increase Emotion Recognition: A Pilot Study</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519822</span></li>
<li><span id="2022MatviienkoEScootAR">of Darmstadt), A. M. (T. U., Munich), F. M. (L. M. U., of Darmstadt), D. S. (T. U., of Darmstadt), R. F. (T. U., of Darmstadt), S. A. (T. U., of Darmstadt), Y. L. (T. U., &amp; of Darmstadt), M. M. (T. U. (2022, April 30). <i>E-ScootAR: Exploring Unimodal Warnings for E-Scooter Riders in Augmented Reality</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519831</span></li>
<li><span id="2022MatviienkoBikeAR">of Darmstadt), A. M. (T. U., Munich), F. M. (L. M. U., of Darmstadt), D. S. (T. U., of Darmstadt), P. S. (T. U., of Darmstadt), S. G. (T. U., &amp; of Darmstadt), M. M. (T. U. (2022, April 30). <i>BikeAR: Understanding Cyclists’ Crossing Decision-Making at Uncontrolled Intersections using Augmented Reality</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3517560</span></li>
<li><span id="2022MatviienkoVRSickness">of Darmstadt), A. M. (T. U., Munich), F. M. (L. M. U., of Darmstadt), M. Z. (T. U., of Darmstadt), L. G. (T. U., of Darmstadt), J. A. (T. U., of Darmstadt), T. S. (T. U., &amp; of Darmstadt), M. M. (T. U. (2022, April 30). <i>Reducing Virtual Reality Sickness for Cyclists in VR Bicycle Simulators</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3501959</span></li>
<li><span id="2022MatviienkoSkyPort">of Darmstadt), A. M. (T. U., Munich), F. M. (L. M. U., of Darmstadt), M. S. (T. U., of Darmstadt), M. F. (T. U., &amp; of Darmstadt), M. M. (T. U. (2022, April 30). <i>SkyPort: Investigating 3D Teleportation Methods in Virtual Environments</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3501983</span></li>
<li><span id="2022PutzeBrainSignals">of Bremen), F. P. (U., of Bremen), S. P. (U., of Bremen), M. S. (U., Institute), C. M. (W. P., &amp; Institute), E. S. (W. P. (2022, April 30). <i>Understanding HCI Practices and Challenges of Experiment Reporting with Brain Signals: Towards Reproducibility and Reuse</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3490554</span></li>
<li><span id="2022MarkyMusic">of Glasgow), K. M. (U., Munich), A. K. (L. M. U., Schallkultur), A. W. (M., Munich), J. K. (L. M. U., Munich), M. H. (L. M. U., of Technology), P. W. W. (C. U., Darmstadt), M. M. (T. U., &amp; University), T. K. (U. (2022, April 30). <i>Intelligent Music Interfaces: When Interactive Assistance and Augmentation Meet Musical Instruments</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3503743</span></li>
<li><span id="2022QueckSpiderClip">TUK), D. Q. (T. U. K., Iannis Albert (Technische Universität Kaiserslautern TUK, U. of B., TUK), P. Z. (T. U. K., TUK), N. B. (T. U. K., Georg Volkmar (Digital Media Lab, U. of B., Bastian Dänekas (Digital Media Lab, U. of B., Rainer Malaka (Digital Media Lab, U. of B., &amp; Marc Herrlich (Technische Universität Kaiserslautern TUK, D. F. K. I. (2022, April 30). <i>SpiderClip: Towards an Open Source System for Wearable Device Simulation in Virtual Reality</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519758</span></li>
<li><span id="2022AlizadehAppropriation">Siegen), F. A. (U., Siegen), A. M. (U., Siegen), A. U. (U., &amp; Siegen), G. S. (U. (2022, April 30). <i>On Appropriation and Nostalgic Reminiscence of Technology </i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519676</span></li>
<li><span id="2022KraussXRPrototyping">Siegen), V. K. (U., of Michigan), M. N. (U., Siegen), F. J. (U., &amp; Alexander Boden (Hochschule Bonn-Rhein-Sieg, F. F. I. T. (2022, April 30). <i>Elements of XR Prototyping: Characterizing the Role and Use of Prototypes in Augmented and Virtual Reality Design</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3517714</span></li>
<li><span id="2022VoelkelChatbots">Munich), S. T. V. (L. M. U., Munich), R. S. (L. M. U., Munich), L. K. (L. M. U., &amp; Munich), S. M. (L. M. U. (2022, April 30). <i>User Perceptions of Extraversion in Chatbots after Repeated Use</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3502058</span></li>
<li><span id="2022ZarghamThatWay">Nima Zargham (Digital Media Lab, U. of B., Dmitry Alexandrovsky (Digital Media Lab, U. of B., Jan Erich (Digital Media Lab, U. of B., Nina Wenig (Digital Media Lab, U. of B., &amp; Rainer Malaka (Digital Media Lab, U. of B. (2022, April 30). <i>"I Want It That Way": Exploring Users’ Customization and Personalization Preferences for Home Assistants</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519843</span></li>
<li><span id="2022ZarghamCatch">Nima Zargham (Digital Media Lab, U. of B., Johannes Pfau (Digital Media Lab, U. of B., Tobias Schnackenberg (Digital Media Lab, U. of B., &amp; Rainer Malaka (Digital Media Lab, U. of B. (2022, April 30). <i>"I Didn’t Catch That, But I’ll Try My Best”: Anticipatory Error Handling in a Voice Controlled Game</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3502115</span></li>
<li><span id="2022ElAgroudySharedMemories">Munich), P. E. A. (L. M. U., Ms. Mennatallah Saleh (Hamm-Lippstadt University of Applied Science, T. U. B., of Applied Sciences), C. S. (H.-L. U., &amp; Munich), A. S. (L. M. U. (2022, April 30). <i>How do Users Expect their Smart Memory Vaults to Utilize Their Shared Memories? </i>.</span></li>
<li><span id="2022CannanureBorders">University), V. K. C. (C. M., Michoacana), C. R.-L. (U., of Cincinnati), A. S. P. (U., University), R. A. V. (C., (IIIT-Delhi), A. T., of Technology), D. G. (T. I., University), F. N. (B., of Washington), N. K. (U., of Virginia), D. N. (U., of Colorado Boulder), D. D. (U., Associates), S. D. (D. &amp;, of Applied Sciences), C. S. (H.-L. U., &amp; Tech), N. K. (G. (2022, April 30). <i>HCI Across Borders: Navigating the shifting borders in CHI</i>. https://hcixb.org/, Website Workshop</span></li>
<li><span id="2022MuenderHapticFidelity">of Bremen), T. M. (U., of Bremen), M. B. (U., of Bremen), A. V. R. (U., of Bremen), R. M. (U., &amp; of Bremen), T. D. (U. (2022, April 30). <i>Haptic Fidelity Framework: Defining the Factors of Realistic Haptic Feedback for Virtual Reality</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3501953</span></li>
<li><span id="2022PourjafarianSurfacesPrinter"><i>Print-A-Sketch: A Handheld Printer for Physical Sketching of Circuits and Sensors on Everyday Surfaces</i>. (2022, April 30). https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3502074</span></li>
<li><span id="2022PflegingAutomatedVehiclesWellbeing">Freiberg), B. P. (T. U. B., of New Hampshire), A. L. K. (U., &amp; College), O. S. (W. (2022, April 30). <i>Automated Vehicles as a Space for Work &amp; Wellbeing</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3503766</span></li>
<li><span id="2022DangGANSlider">of Bayreuth), H. D. (U., Lukas Mecke (LMU Munich, U. B. W. M., &amp; of Bayreuth), D. B. (U. (2022, April 30). <i>GANSlider: How Users Control Generative Models for Images using Multiple Sliders with and without Feedforward Information</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3502141</span></li>
<li><span id="2022RivuRemoteVRStudies">Munich), R. R. (B. U., V. Mäkelä (University of Waterloo, B. U. M., Munich), S. P. (B. U., Munich), S. R. (B. U., Munich), R. P. L. M. U., Munich), Y. Z. (L. M. U., Munich), K. K. (L. M. U., Munich), K. P. (B. U., Munich), Y. A. B. U., Munich), M. H. L. M. U., Munich), A. S. (L. M. U., &amp; Munich), F. A. (B. U. (2022, April 30). <i>Remote VR Studies: A Framework for Running Virtual Reality Studies Remotely Via Participant-Owned HMDs</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3472617</span></li>
<li><span id="2022RixenPersonalInformationAR">Jan Ole Rixen (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., Mark Colley (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., Ali Askari (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., Jan Gugenheimer (Télécom Paris - LTCI, I. P. de P., &amp; Enrico Rukzio (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U. (2022, April 30). <i>Consent in the Age of AR: Investigating The Comfort With Displaying Personal Information in Augmented Reality</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3502140</span></li>
<li><span id="2022SaadCovid19UsageAndAuthentication">of Duisburg-Essen), A. S. (U., of Duisburg-Essen), U. G. (U., Munich), L. M. (B. U., of Duisburg-Essen), M. K. (U., Munich), F. A. (B. U., &amp; of Duisburg-Essen), S. S. (U. (2022, April 30). <i>Mask removal isn’t always convenient in public! - The Impact of the Covid-19 Pandemic on Device Usage and User Authentication</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519804</span></li>
<li><span id="2022GruenefeldVRception">of Duisburg-Essen), U. G. (U., of Duisburg-Essen), J. A. (U., Florian Mathis (University of Glasgow, U. of E., of Duisburg-Essen), S. S. (U., of Glasgow), M. K. (U., Jan Gugenheimer (Institut Polytechnique de Paris, L. T. C. I., Télécom Paris, &amp; and Sven Mayer (LMU Munich). (2022, April 30). <i>VRception: Rapid Prototyping of Cross-Reality Systems in Virtual Reality</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3501821</span></li>
<li><span id="2022ColleyEffectsAutomatedVehicles">Mark Colley (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., Elvedin Bajrovic (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., &amp; Enrico Rukzio (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U. (2022). <i>Effects of Pedestrian Behavior, Time Pressure, and Repeated Exposure on Crossing Decisions in Front of Automated Vehicles Equipped with External Communication</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3517571</span></li>
<li><span id="2022MakhsadovVRySmart">DFKI), A. M. (S. U. &amp;, DFKI), D. D. (S. U. &amp;, DFKI), A. Z. (S. U. &amp;, DFKI), F. K. (S. U. &amp;, University), K. M. (S., &amp; DFKI), A. K. (S. U. &amp;. (2022, April 30). <i>VRySmart: a Framework for Embedding Smart Devices in Virtual Reality</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519717</span></li>
<li><span id="2022SchneiderSustainable">of Waterloo), O. S. (U., Bruno Fruchard (Univ. Lille, I., Dresden), D. W. (H. T. W., of Waterloo), B. R. J. (U., Dresden), G. F. (H. T. W., DFKI), D. D. (S. U. &amp;, &amp; Paul Strohmeier (Sensorimotor Interaction, M. P. I. (2022, April 30). <i>Sustainable Haptic Design: Improving Collaboration, Sharing, and Reuse in Haptic Design Research</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3503734</span></li>
<li><span id="2022BrockerActuated"><i>Actuated Materials and Soft Robotics Strategies for Human Computer Interaction Design</i>. (2022, April 30). https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3503711</span></li>
<li><span id="2022BrockerSoRoCAD"><i>SoRoCAD: A Design Tool for the Building Blocks of Pneumatic Soft Robotics</i>. (2022, April 30). https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519770</span></li>
<li><span id="2022DoellingerMindandBody">Nina Döllinger (University of Würzburg, H.-T. S., Erik Wolf (University of Würzburg, H.-C. I., David Mal (University of Würzburg, H.-C. I., Nico Erdmannsdörfer (University of Würzburg, H.-T. S., Mario Botsch (TU Dortmund, C. G. G., Marc Erich Latoschik (University of Würzburg, H.-C. I., &amp; Carolin Wienrich (University of Würzburg, H.-T. S. (2022, April 30). <i>Virtual Reality for Mind and Body: Does the Sense of Embodiment Towards a Virtual Body Affect Physical Body Awareness?</i> https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519613</span></li>
<li><span id="2022ReipschlaegerAvatAR"><i>AvatAR: An Immersive Analysis Environment for Human Motion Data Combining Interactive 3D Avatars and Trajectories</i>. (2022, April 30). https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3517676</span></li>
<li><span id="2022HuangProxemics">Munich), A. H. (L. M. U., Munich), P. K. (L. M. U., Munich), F. C. (L. M. U., for Humans, L. C. (C., Technology, C. U. of T., &amp; Munich), R. W. (L. M. U. (2022, April 30). <i>Proxemics for Human-Agent Interaction in Augmented Reality</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3517593</span></li>
<li><span id="2022HirzleEyeStrain">University), T. H. (U., University), F. F. (U., University), J. K. (U., University), P. J. (U., Paris), J. G. (T., University), E. R. (U., &amp; of Stuttgart), A. B. (U. (2022, April 30). <i>Understanding, Addressing, and Analysing Digital Eye Strain in Virtual Reality Head-Mounted Displays</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3492802</span></li>
<li><span id="2022MehrotraScent">Siddharth Mehrotra (Delft University of Technology, N., Anke Brocker (RWTH Aachen University, G., Marianna Obrist (University College London, U. K., &amp; Jan Borchers (RWTH Aachen University, G. (2022, April 30). <i>The Scent of Collaboration: Exploring the Effect of Smell on Social Interactions</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519632</span></li>
<li><span id="2022WolfBreakfast">Sara Wolf (Institute Human-Computer Media, G., JMU Würzburg, of Psychology, F. M. (D., Ergonomics, G., TU Berlin, of Protestant Theology, S. L. (I., Religious Education, G., JMU Würzburg, of Protestant Theology, I. N. (I., Religious Education, G., JMU Würzburg, &amp; Jörn Hurtienne (Chair of Psychological Ergonomics, G., JMU Würzburg. (2022, April 30). <i>Spirituality at the Breakfast Table: Experiences of Christian Online Worship Services</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519856</span></li></ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[of Technology), A. H. (K. I., of Bamberg), F. N. (U., of Technology), A. P. (K. I., of Bamberg), D. H. (U., &amp; of Technology), P. M. (K. I. (2022, May 1). Standing out among the daily spam: How to catch website owners’ attention by means of vulnerability notifications. https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519847 (KIT), M. L., (KIT), P. T., &amp; (KIT), A. M. (2022, May 1). EyeMeet: A Joint Attention Support System for Remote Meetings. https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519792 (KIT), M. R., (CMU), B. M., &amp; (KIT), A. M. (2022, May 1). ONYX - User Interfaces for Assisting in Interactive Task Learning for Natural Language Interfaces of Data Visualization Tools. https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519793 University), A. S. N. (S., &amp; University), J. S. (S. (2022, April 30). Next Steps in Epidermal Computing: Opportunities and Challenges for Soft On-Skin Devices. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3517668 Darmstadt), S. G. (T. U., München), J. R. (L. M. U., Darmstadt), D. S. (T. U., München), F. M. (L. M. U., Darmstadt), M. S. (T. U., Darmstadt), J. R. (T. U., Darmstadt), A. M. (T. U., &amp; München), M. M. (L. M. U. (2022, April 30). Smooth as Steel Wool: Effects of Visual Stimuli on the Haptic Perception of Roughness in Virtual Reality. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3517454 Thomas Muender (Digital Media Lab, U. of B., Anke Reinschluessel (Digital Media Lab, U. of B., Daniela Salzmann (University Hospital for Visceral Surgery, P. I. U. S.-H., Carl von Ossietzky University of Oldenburg, (cirp GmbH), T. L., for Digital Medicine MEVIS), A. S. (F. I., Dirk Weyhe (University Hospital for Visceral Surgery, P. I. U. S.-H., Carl von Ossietzky University of Oldenburg, Tanja Döring (Digital Media Lab, U. of B., &amp; Rainer Malaka (Digital Media Lab, U. of B. (2022, April 30). Evaluating Soft Organ-Shaped Tangibles for Medical Virtual Reality. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519715 Where Should We Put It? Layout and Placement Strategies of Documents in Augmented Reality for Collaborative Sensemaking. (2022, April 30). https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3501946 Investigating Usability and User Experience of Individually Verifiable Internet Voting Schemes. (2022, April 30). https://doi.org/10.1145/3459604 Keunwoo Park (Hasso Plattner Institute, G., Potsdam, Conrad Lempert (Hasso Plattner Institute, G., Potsdam, Muhammad Abdullah (Hasso Plattner Institute, G., Potsdam, Shohei Katakura (Hasso Plattner Institute, G., Potsdam, Jotaro Shigeyama (Hasso Plattner Institute, G., Potsdam, Thijs Roumen (Hasso Plattner Institute, G., Potsdam, &amp; Patrick Baudisch (Hasso Plattner Institute, G., Potsdam. (2022, April 30). FoolProofJoint: Reducing Assembly Errors of Laser Cut 3D Models by Means of Custom Joint Patterns. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3501919 Dresden), S. E. (T. U., Dresden), K. K. (T. U., Dresden), A. P. (T. U., &amp; Dresden), R. D. (T. U. (2022, April 30). STRAIDE: A Research Platform for Shape-Changing Spatial Displays based on Actuated Strings. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3517462 Munich), M. W. (L. M. U., of Regensburg), N. H. (U., Munich), A. S. (L. M. U., &amp; Munich), S. S. F. (L. M. U. (2022, April 30). Automating Contextual Privacy Policies: Design and Evaluation of a Production Tool for Digital Consumer Privacy Awareness. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3517688 Munich), M. W. (L. M. U., Munich), S. S. F. (L. M. U., University), L. Z. (U., Munich), A. S. (L. M. U., &amp; of Technology), P. W. W. (C. U. (2022, April 30). It Is Not Always Discovery Time: Four Pragmatic Approaches in Designing AI Systems. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3501943 Tobias Drey (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., Patrick Albus (Institute of Psychology + Education, U. U., Simon der Kinderen (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., Maximilian Milo (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., Thilo Segschneider (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., Linda Chanzab (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., Michael Rietzler (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., Tina Seufert (Institute of Psychology + Education, U. U., &amp; Enrico Rukzio (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U. (2022, April 30). Towards Collaborative Learning in Virtual Reality: A Comparison of Co-Located Symmetric and Asymmetric Pair-Learning. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3517641 Yasmeen Abdrabou (Bundeswehr University Munich, U. of G., Munich), J. S. (B. U., Egypt), A. S. (F. L. L. C., Ken Pfeuffer (Aarhus University, B. U. M., of Bayreuth), D. B. (U., of Glasgow), M. K. (U., &amp; Munich), F. A. (B. U. (2022, April 30). "Your Eyes Tell You Have Used This Password Before": Identifying Password Reuse from Gaze and Keystroke Dynamics. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3517531 Sarah Prange (University of the Bundeswehr Munich, L. M. U. M., of the Bundeswehr Munich), S. D. R. (U., Munich), T. D. (L. M. U., &amp; of the Bundeswehr Munich), F. A. (U. (2022, April 30). "Where did you first meet the owner?” – Exploring Usable Authentication for Smart Home Visitors. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519777 Munich), V. V. (L. M. U., Sarah Prange (University of the Bundeswehr Munich, L. M. U. M., &amp; of the Bundeswehr Munich), F. A. (U. (2022, April 30). PriCheck - An Online Assistant for Smart Device Purchases. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519827 Katta Spiel (Human-Computer Interaction Group, T. U. W., Weimar), E. H. (B.-U., of Florida), R. M. W. (U., &amp; of Sussex), J. G. (U. (2022, April 30). ADHD and Technology Research – Investigated by Neurodivergent Readers. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445196 Pet-Robot or Appliance? Care Home Residents with Dementia Respond to a Zoomorphic Floor Washing Robot. (2022, April 30). https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3517463 Evgeny Stemasov (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., Tobias Wagner (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., Jan Gugenheimer (Télécom Paris - LTCI, I. P. de P., &amp; Enrico Rukzio (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U. (2022, April 30). ShapeFindAR: Exploring In-Situ Spatial Search for Physical Artifact Retrieval using Mixed Reality . https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3517682 Munich), J. L. (L. M. U., Munich), F. F. (L. M. U., Group), S. C. (B. M. W., &amp; Munich), A. B. (L. M. U. (2022, April 30). Towards Balancing Real-World Awareness and VR Immersion in Mobile VR. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519824 of Stuttgart), A. S. C. (U., of Stuttgart), N. H. (U., of Stuttgart), N. B. S. (U., of Stuttgart), V. B. (U., &amp; of Stuttgart), M. S. (U. (2022, April 30). cARdLearner: Using Expressive Virtual Agents when Learning Vocabulary in Augmented Reality. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519631 Natalie Hube (Mercedes-Benz AG, U. of S., Kresimir Vidackovic (Hochschule der Medien, U. of A. S., &amp; of Stuttgart), M. S. (U. (2022, April 30). Using Expressive Avatars to Increase Emotion Recognition: A Pilot Study. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519822 of Darmstadt), A. M. (T. U., Munich), F. M. (L. M. U., of Darmstadt), D. S. (T. U., of Darmstadt), R. F. (T. U., of Darmstadt), S. A. (T. U., of Darmstadt), Y. L. (T. U., &amp; of Darmstadt), M. M. (T. U. (2022, April 30). E-ScootAR: Exploring Unimodal Warnings for E-Scooter Riders in Augmented Reality. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519831 of Darmstadt), A. M. (T. U., Munich), F. M. (L. M. U., of Darmstadt), D. S. (T. U., of Darmstadt), P. S. (T. U., of Darmstadt), S. G. (T. U., &amp; of Darmstadt), M. M. (T. U. (2022, April 30). BikeAR: Understanding Cyclists’ Crossing Decision-Making at Uncontrolled Intersections using Augmented Reality. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3517560 of Darmstadt), A. M. (T. U., Munich), F. M. (L. M. U., of Darmstadt), M. Z. (T. U., of Darmstadt), L. G. (T. U., of Darmstadt), J. A. (T. U., of Darmstadt), T. S. (T. U., &amp; of Darmstadt), M. M. (T. U. (2022, April 30). Reducing Virtual Reality Sickness for Cyclists in VR Bicycle Simulators. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3501959 of Darmstadt), A. M. (T. U., Munich), F. M. (L. M. U., of Darmstadt), M. S. (T. U., of Darmstadt), M. F. (T. U., &amp; of Darmstadt), M. M. (T. U. (2022, April 30). SkyPort: Investigating 3D Teleportation Methods in Virtual Environments. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3501983 of Bremen), F. P. (U., of Bremen), S. P. (U., of Bremen), M. S. (U., Institute), C. M. (W. P., &amp; Institute), E. S. (W. P. (2022, April 30). Understanding HCI Practices and Challenges of Experiment Reporting with Brain Signals: Towards Reproducibility and Reuse. https://doi.org/10.1145/3490554 of Glasgow), K. M. (U., Munich), A. K. (L. M. U., Schallkultur), A. W. (M., Munich), J. K. (L. M. U., Munich), M. H. (L. M. U., of Technology), P. W. W. (C. U., Darmstadt), M. M. (T. U., &amp; University), T. K. (U. (2022, April 30). Intelligent Music Interfaces: When Interactive Assistance and Augmentation Meet Musical Instruments. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3503743 TUK), D. Q. (T. U. K., Iannis Albert (Technische Universität Kaiserslautern TUK, U. of B., TUK), P. Z. (T. U. K., TUK), N. B. (T. U. K., Georg Volkmar (Digital Media Lab, U. of B., Bastian Dänekas (Digital Media Lab, U. of B., Rainer Malaka (Digital Media Lab, U. of B., &amp; Marc Herrlich (Technische Universität Kaiserslautern TUK, D. F. K. I. (2022, April 30). SpiderClip: Towards an Open Source System for Wearable Device Simulation in Virtual Reality. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519758 Siegen), F. A. (U., Siegen), A. M. (U., Siegen), A. U. (U., &amp; Siegen), G. S. (U. (2022, April 30). On Appropriation and Nostalgic Reminiscence of Technology . https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519676 Siegen), V. K. (U., of Michigan), M. N. (U., Siegen), F. J. (U., &amp; Alexander Boden (Hochschule Bonn-Rhein-Sieg, F. F. I. T. (2022, April 30). Elements of XR Prototyping: Characterizing the Role and Use of Prototypes in Augmented and Virtual Reality Design. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3517714 Munich), S. T. V. (L. M. U., Munich), R. S. (L. M. U., Munich), L. K. (L. M. U., &amp; Munich), S. M. (L. M. U. (2022, April 30). User Perceptions of Extraversion in Chatbots after Repeated Use. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3502058 Nima Zargham (Digital Media Lab, U. of B., Dmitry Alexandrovsky (Digital Media Lab, U. of B., Jan Erich (Digital Media Lab, U. of B., Nina Wenig (Digital Media Lab, U. of B., &amp; Rainer Malaka (Digital Media Lab, U. of B. (2022, April 30). "I Want It That Way": Exploring Users’ Customization and Personalization Preferences for Home Assistants. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519843 Nima Zargham (Digital Media Lab, U. of B., Johannes Pfau (Digital Media Lab, U. of B., Tobias Schnackenberg (Digital Media Lab, U. of B., &amp; Rainer Malaka (Digital Media Lab, U. of B. (2022, April 30). "I Didn’t Catch That, But I’ll Try My Best”: Anticipatory Error Handling in a Voice Controlled Game. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3502115 Munich), P. E. A. (L. M. U., Ms. Mennatallah Saleh (Hamm-Lippstadt University of Applied Science, T. U. B., of Applied Sciences), C. S. (H.-L. U., &amp; Munich), A. S. (L. M. U. (2022, April 30). How do Users Expect their Smart Memory Vaults to Utilize Their Shared Memories? . University), V. K. C. (C. M., Michoacana), C. R.-L. (U., of Cincinnati), A. S. P. (U., University), R. A. V. (C., (IIIT-Delhi), A. T., of Technology), D. G. (T. I., University), F. N. (B., of Washington), N. K. (U., of Virginia), D. N. (U., of Colorado Boulder), D. D. (U., Associates), S. D. (D. &amp;, of Applied Sciences), C. S. (H.-L. U., &amp; Tech), N. K. (G. (2022, April 30). HCI Across Borders: Navigating the shifting borders in CHI. https://hcixb.org/, Website Workshop of Bremen), T. M. (U., of Bremen), M. B. (U., of Bremen), A. V. R. (U., of Bremen), R. M. (U., &amp; of Bremen), T. D. (U. (2022, April 30). Haptic Fidelity Framework: Defining the Factors of Realistic Haptic Feedback for Virtual Reality. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3501953 Print-A-Sketch: A Handheld Printer for Physical Sketching of Circuits and Sensors on Everyday Surfaces. (2022, April 30). https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3502074 Freiberg), B. P. (T. U. B., of New Hampshire), A. L. K. (U., &amp; College), O. S. (W. (2022, April 30). Automated Vehicles as a Space for Work &amp; Wellbeing. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3503766 of Bayreuth), H. D. (U., Lukas Mecke (LMU Munich, U. B. W. M., &amp; of Bayreuth), D. B. (U. (2022, April 30). GANSlider: How Users Control Generative Models for Images using Multiple Sliders with and without Feedforward Information. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3502141 Munich), R. R. (B. U., V. Mäkelä (University of Waterloo, B. U. M., Munich), S. P. (B. U., Munich), S. R. (B. U., Munich), R. P. L. M. U., Munich), Y. Z. (L. M. U., Munich), K. K. (L. M. U., Munich), K. P. (B. U., Munich), Y. A. B. U., Munich), M. H. L. M. U., Munich), A. S. (L. M. U., &amp; Munich), F. A. (B. U. (2022, April 30). Remote VR Studies: A Framework for Running Virtual Reality Studies Remotely Via Participant-Owned HMDs. https://doi.org/10.1145/3472617 Jan Ole Rixen (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., Mark Colley (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., Ali Askari (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., Jan Gugenheimer (Télécom Paris - LTCI, I. P. de P., &amp; Enrico Rukzio (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U. (2022, April 30). Consent in the Age of AR: Investigating The Comfort With Displaying Personal Information in Augmented Reality. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3502140 of Duisburg-Essen), A. S. (U., of Duisburg-Essen), U. G. (U., Munich), L. M. (B. U., of Duisburg-Essen), M. K. (U., Munich), F. A. (B. U., &amp; of Duisburg-Essen), S. S. (U. (2022, April 30). Mask removal isn’t always convenient in public! - The Impact of the Covid-19 Pandemic on Device Usage and User Authentication. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519804 of Duisburg-Essen), U. G. (U., of Duisburg-Essen), J. A. (U., Florian Mathis (University of Glasgow, U. of E., of Duisburg-Essen), S. S. (U., of Glasgow), M. K. (U., Jan Gugenheimer (Institut Polytechnique de Paris, L. T. C. I., Télécom Paris, &amp; and Sven Mayer (LMU Munich). (2022, April 30). VRception: Rapid Prototyping of Cross-Reality Systems in Virtual Reality. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3501821 Mark Colley (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., Elvedin Bajrovic (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., &amp; Enrico Rukzio (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U. (2022). Effects of Pedestrian Behavior, Time Pressure, and Repeated Exposure on Crossing Decisions in Front of Automated Vehicles Equipped with External Communication. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3517571 DFKI), A. M. (S. U. &amp;, DFKI), D. D. (S. U. &amp;, DFKI), A. Z. (S. U. &amp;, DFKI), F. K. (S. U. &amp;, University), K. M. (S., &amp; DFKI), A. K. (S. U. &amp;. (2022, April 30). VRySmart: a Framework for Embedding Smart Devices in Virtual Reality. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519717 of Waterloo), O. S. (U., Bruno Fruchard (Univ. Lille, I., Dresden), D. W. (H. T. W., of Waterloo), B. R. J. (U., Dresden), G. F. (H. T. W., DFKI), D. D. (S. U. &amp;, &amp; Paul Strohmeier (Sensorimotor Interaction, M. P. I. (2022, April 30). Sustainable Haptic Design: Improving Collaboration, Sharing, and Reuse in Haptic Design Research. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3503734 Actuated Materials and Soft Robotics Strategies for Human Computer Interaction Design. (2022, April 30). https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3503711 SoRoCAD: A Design Tool for the Building Blocks of Pneumatic Soft Robotics. (2022, April 30). https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519770 Nina Döllinger (University of Würzburg, H.-T. S., Erik Wolf (University of Würzburg, H.-C. I., David Mal (University of Würzburg, H.-C. I., Nico Erdmannsdörfer (University of Würzburg, H.-T. S., Mario Botsch (TU Dortmund, C. G. G., Marc Erich Latoschik (University of Würzburg, H.-C. I., &amp; Carolin Wienrich (University of Würzburg, H.-T. S. (2022, April 30). Virtual Reality for Mind and Body: Does the Sense of Embodiment Towards a Virtual Body Affect Physical Body Awareness? https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519613 AvatAR: An Immersive Analysis Environment for Human Motion Data Combining Interactive 3D Avatars and Trajectories. (2022, April 30). https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3517676 Munich), A. H. (L. M. U., Munich), P. K. (L. M. U., Munich), F. C. (L. M. U., for Humans, L. C. (C., Technology, C. U. of T., &amp; Munich), R. W. (L. M. U. (2022, April 30). Proxemics for Human-Agent Interaction in Augmented Reality. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3517593 University), T. H. (U., University), F. F. (U., University), J. K. (U., University), P. J. (U., Paris), J. G. (T., University), E. R. (U., &amp; of Stuttgart), A. B. (U. (2022, April 30). Understanding, Addressing, and Analysing Digital Eye Strain in Virtual Reality Head-Mounted Displays. https://doi.org/10.1145/3492802 Siddharth Mehrotra (Delft University of Technology, N., Anke Brocker (RWTH Aachen University, G., Marianna Obrist (University College London, U. K., &amp; Jan Borchers (RWTH Aachen University, G. (2022, April 30). The Scent of Collaboration: Exploring the Effect of Smell on Social Interactions. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519632 Sara Wolf (Institute Human-Computer Media, G., JMU Würzburg, of Psychology, F. M. (D., Ergonomics, G., TU Berlin, of Protestant Theology, S. L. (I., Religious Education, G., JMU Würzburg, of Protestant Theology, I. N. (I., Religious Education, G., JMU Würzburg, &amp; Jörn Hurtienne (Chair of Psychological Ergonomics, G., JMU Würzburg. (2022, April 30). Spirituality at the Breakfast Table: Experiences of Christian Online Worship Services. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491101.3519856]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">References 2020</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="References 2020" /><published>2023-03-01T15:56:47+01:00</published><updated>2023-03-01T15:56:47+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/"><![CDATA[<ol class="bibliography"><li><span id="CarrosExploring">Siegen), F. C. (U., Siegen), J. M. (U., Siegen), D. L. (U., Siegen), D. U. (U., Siegen), S. M. (U., Siegen), I. K. (U., Siegen), R. W. (U., Siegen), D. R. (U., Siegen), M. H. (U., &amp; Siegen), V. W. (U. (2020, May 1). Exploring Human-Robot Interaction with the Elderly: Results from a Ten-Week Case Study in a Care Home. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376402</span></li>
<li><span id="KumarSelf">University), Y. K. M. (S., College), X.-D. Y. (D., University), M. L. (A., University), M. C. (S., of Regensburg), N. H. (U., Research), S. H. (M., University), M. J. (S., of Technolgy), N. A. (G. I., &amp; of Technology), G. D. A. (G. I. (2020). SelfSustainableCHI: Self-Powered Sustainable Interfaces and Interactions. In <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. ACM. https://doi.org/10.1145/3334480.3375167</span></li>
<li><span id="KurzeGuess">of Technology), A. K. (C. U., of Technology), A. B. (C. U., of Technology), S. T. (C. U., of Technology), M. S. (C. U., of Technology), M. E. (C. U., of Technology), M. B. (Q. U., &amp; of Applied Sciences), A. B. (A. U. (2020, May 1). Guess the Data: Data Work to Understand How People Make Sense of and Use Simple Sensor Data from Homes. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376273</span></li>
<li><span id="KlamkaWatchStrap">Dresden), K. K. (T. U., Dresden), T. H. (T. U., &amp; Dresden), R. D. (T. U. (2020, April 26). Watch+Strap: Extending Smartwatches with Interactive StrapDisplays. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376199</span></li>
<li><span id="KlamkaRapid">Dresden), K. K. (T. U., Dresden), R. D. (T. U., &amp; University), J. S. (S. (2020, April 26). Rapid Iron-On User Interfaces: Hands-on Fabrication of Interactive Textile Prototypes. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376220</span></li>
<li><span id="DuerrNurseCare">of Konstanz), M. D. (U., of Konstanz), C. G. (U., of Konstanz), U. P. (U., &amp; of Konstanz), H. R. (U. (2020, April 26). NurseCare: Design and ‘In-The-Wild’ Evaluation of a Mobile System to Promote the Ergonomic Transfer of Patients. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376851</span></li>
<li><span id="MuellerIntegration">University), F. ’F. M. (M., of Chicago), P. L. (U., of Copenhagen / Saarland University), P. S. (U., Tech), W. J. (C., University), C. S. (S., Europe), M. W. (H. R. I., of Auckland), S. N. (U., of Essex), M. O. (U., University), Z. L. (M., University), J. D. (M., of Chicago), J. N. (U., University), E. M. G. (N., of Copenhagen), D. S. (N. T. N. U. / I. T. U., (Microsoft), J. G., University), S. G. (D., University), K. K. (K., researcher), T. E. (I., Technologies), S. G. (C. A., of Tokyo), M. I. (U., … Lab), P. M. (M. I. T. M. (2020, April 26). Next Steps in Human-Computer Integration. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376242</span></li>
<li><span id="ZagermannStudying">of Konstanz), J. Z. (U., of Konstanz), U. P. (U., von Bauer (University of Konstanz), P., of Konstanz), D. F. (U., &amp; of Konstanz), H. R. (U. (2020, April 26). ’It’s in my other hand!’ - Studying the Interplay of Interaction Techniques and Multi-Tablet Activities. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376540</span></li>
<li><span id="PfauBot">of Bremen), J. P. (U., University), J. D. S. (N., of Bremen), I. B. (U., &amp; of Bremen), R. M. (U. (2020, April 26). Bot or not? User Perceptions of Player Substitution with Deep Player Behavior Models. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376223</span></li>
<li><span id="PfauEnemy">of Bremen), J. P. (U., University), J. D. S. (N., &amp; of Bremen), R. M. (U. (2020, April 26). Enemy Within: Long-term Motivation Effects of Deep Player Behavior Models for Dynamic Difficulty Adjustment. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376423</span></li>
<li><span id="PutzeBreaking">of Bremen), S. P. (U., of Bremen), D. A. (U., of Bremen), F. P. (U., of Bremen), S. H. (U., University), J. D. S. (N., &amp; of Bremen), R. M. (U. (2020, April 26). Breaking The Experience: Effects of Questionnaires in VR User Studies. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376144</span></li>
<li><span id="AlexandrovskyExamining">of Bremen), D. A. (U., of Bremen), S. P. (U., of Bremen), M. B. (U., of Bremen), S. H. (U., of Bremen), P. M. (U., of Bremen), D. W. (U., of Bremen), R. M. (U., &amp; University), J. D. S. (N. (2020, April 26). Examining Design Choices of Questionnaires in VR User Studies. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376260</span></li>
<li><span id="SchroederRobustness">of Bremen), C. S. (U., of Bremen), S. M. K. A. Z. (U., of Bremen), M. H. U. P. (U., of Bremen), S. M. (U., &amp; of Bremen), G. Z. (U. (2020, April 26). Robustness of Eye Movement Biometrics Against Varying Stimuli and Varying Trajectory Length. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376534</span></li>
<li><span id="PutzePlatform">of Bremen), F. P. (U., of Bremen), T. I. (U., of Bremen), T. S. (U., &amp; University), W. S. (S. F. (2020, April 26). Platform for Studying Self-Repairing Auto-Corrections in Mobile Text Entry based on Brain Activity, Gaze, and Context. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376815</span></li>
<li><span id="FrommelRecognizing">of Saskatchewan), J. F. (U. U. / U., of Saskatchewan), V. S. (U., of Saskatchewan), A. E. D. (U., of Saskatchewan), C. J. (U., of Saskatchewan), M. K. M. (U., &amp; of Saskatchewan), R. L. M. (U. (2020, April 26). Recognizing Affiliation: Using Behavioural Traces to Predict the Quality of Social Interactions in Online Games. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376446</span></li>
<li><span id="WolfUnderstanding">University), D. W. (U., University), J. G. (U., University), M. C. (U., &amp; University), E. R. (U. (2020, April 26). Understanding the Heisenberg Effect of Spatial Interaction: A Selection Induced Error for Spatially Tracked Input Devices. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376876</span></li>
<li><span id="WolfJump">University), D. W. (U., University), K. R. (U., University), C. K. (U., &amp; University), E. R. (U. (2020, April 26). JumpVR: Jump-Based Locomotion Augmentation for Virtual Reality. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376243</span></li>
<li><span id="StemasovMix">University), E. S. (U., University), T. W. (U., University), J. G. (U., &amp; University), E. R. (U. (2020, April 26). Mix&amp;Match: Towards Omitting Modelling through In-Situ Alteration and Remixing of Model Repository Artifacts in Mixed Reality. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376839</span></li>
<li><span id="ColleyTowards">University), M. C. (U., University), M. W. (U., University), J. G. (U., University), A. A. (U., &amp; University), E. R. (U. (2020, April 26). Towards Inclusive External Communication of Autonomous Vehicles for Pedestrians with Vision Impairments. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376472</span></li>
<li><span id="DreyVRSketchIn">University), T. D. (U., University), J. G. (U., University), J. K. (U., University), M. M. (U., &amp; University), E. R. (U. (2020, April 26). VRSketchIn: Exploring the Design Space of Pen and Tablet Interaction for 3D Sketching in Virtual Reality. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376628</span></li>
<li><span id="RietzlerTelewalk">University), M. R. (U., University), M. D. (U., University), T. D. (U., &amp; University), E. R. (U. (2020, April 26). Telewalk: Towards Free and Endless Walking in Room-Scale Virtual Reality. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376821</span></li>
<li><span id="OsmersGetting">Clausthal), N. O. (T. U., &amp; Clausthal), M. P. (T. U. (2020, April 26). Getting out of Out of Sight: Evaluation of AR Mechanisms for Awareness and Orientation Support in Occluded Multi-Room Settings. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376742</span></li>
<li><span id="BuettnerAugmented">OWL), S. B. (T. U. C. / T. H., Clausthal), M. P. (T. U., &amp; OWL), C. R. (T. H. (2020, April 26). Augmented Reality Training for Industrial Assembly Work – Are Projection-based AR Assistive Systems an Appropriate Tool for Assembly Training? <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376720</span></li>
<li><span id="SubramanianTractus">(RWTH), K. S., (RWTH), J. M., &amp; (RWTH), J. B. (2020, April 26). TRACTUS: Understanding and Supporting Source Code Experimentation in Hypothesis-Driven Data Science. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376764</span></li>
<li><span id="WackerHeatmaps">(RWTH), P. W., (RWTH), A. W., (RWTH), S. V., &amp; (RWTH), J. B. (2020, April 26). Heatmaps, Shadows, Bubbles, Rays: Comparing Mid-Air Pen Position Visualizations in Handheld AR. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376848</span></li>
<li><span id="VoelkerGaze">(RWTH), S. V., (RWTH), S. H., Zurich), C. H. (E. T. H., University), C. R. (A., &amp; London), N. M. (U. C. (2020, April 26). GazeConduits: Calibration-Free Cross-Device Collaboration through Gaze and Touch. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376578</span></li>
<li><span id="VoelkerHeadReach">(RWTH), S. V., (RWTH), S. H., (RWTH), C. C., &amp; University), C. R. (A. (2020, April 26). HeadReach: Using Head Tracking to Increase Reachability on Mobile Touch Devices. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376868</span></li>
<li><span id="Marky3D">Darmstadt), K. M. (T. U., Darmstadt), M. S. (T. U., Darmstadt), V. Z. (T. U., Darmstadt), M. H. (T. U., Design), K. K. (K. M., &amp; Darmstadt), M. M. (T. U. (2020, April 26). 3D-Auth: Two-Factor Authentication with Personalized 3D-Printed Items. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376189</span></li>
<li><span id="WillichPodoportation">von Willich (TU Darmstadt), J., Darmstadt), M. S. (T. U., Darmstadt), F. M. (T. U., Darmstadt), D. S. (T. U., &amp; Darmstadt), M. M. (T. U. (2020, April 26). Podoportation: Foot-Based Locomotion in Virtual Reality. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376626</span></li>
<li><span id="MarkyImproving">Darmstadt), K. M. (T. U., Darmstadt), V. Z. (T. U., GmbH), M. F. (C., Darmstadt), J. D. (T. U., Darmstadt), K. B. (T. U., &amp; Darmstadt), M. M. (T. U. (2020, April 26). Improving the Usability and UX of the Swiss Internet Voting Interface. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376769</span></li>
<li><span id="GuentherTherminator">Darmstadt), S. G. (T. U., Darmstadt), F. M. (T. U., Darmstadt), D. S. (T. U., (GUC), O. E., Darmstadt), M. S. (T. U., &amp; Darmstadt), M. M. (T. U. (2020, April 26). Therminator: Understanding the Interdependency of Visual and On-Body Thermal Feedback in Virtual Reality. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376195</span></li>
<li><span id="MuellerWalk">Darmstadt), F. M. (T. U., Darmstadt), M. S. (T. U., Darmstadt), D. S. (T. U., Darmstadt), S. G. (T. U., Darmstadt), M. F. (T. U., &amp; Darmstadt), M. M. (T. U. (2020, April 26). Walk The Line: Leveraging Lateral Shifts of the Walking Path as an Input Modality for Head-Mounted Displays. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376852</span></li>
<li><span id="MostajeranAugmented">Hamburg), F. M. (U., Hamburg), F. S. (U., Hamburg), O. A. (U., of Ioannina), D. G. (U., &amp; of Ioannina), D. F. (U. (2020, April 26). Augmented Reality for Older Adults: Exploring Acceptability of Virtual Coaches for Home-based Balance Training in an Aging Population. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376565</span></li>
<li><span id="FreiwaldWalking">Hamburg), J. P. F. (U., Hamburg), O. A. (U., Hamburg), O. J. (U., &amp; Hamburg), F. S. (U. (2020, April 26). Walking by Cycling: A Novel In-Place Locomotion User Interface for Seated Virtual Reality Experiences. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376574</span></li>
<li><span id="UnbehaunSocial">Siegen), D. U. (U., Siegen), K. A. (U., Bonn-Rhein-Siegen), D. D. V. (H., Siegen), P. D. T. (U., Siegen), R. W. (U., Siegen), D. R. (U., &amp; Siegen), V. W. (U. (2020, April 26). Social Technology Appropriation in Dementia: Investigating the Role of Caregivers in engaging People with Dementia with a Videogame-based Training System. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376648</span></li>
<li><span id="LaschkeMeaningful">Siegen), M. L. (U., Healthineers), C. B. (S., Siegen), R. N. (U., &amp; Siegen), M. H. (U. (2020, April 26). Meaningful Technology at Work – A Reflective Design Case of Improving Radiologists’ Wellbeing Through Medical Technology. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376710</span></li>
<li><span id="UhdeFairness">Siegen), A. U. (U., GmbH), N. S. (E., GmbH), D. P. W. (E., &amp; Siegen), M. H. (U. (2020, April 26). Fairness and Decision-making in Collaborative Shift Scheduling Systems. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376656</span></li>
<li><span id="MelfiUnderstanding">(KIT-SZS), G. M., (KIT-SZS), K. M., (KIT-SZS), T. S., (KIT-SZS), G. J., &amp; (KIT-SZS), R. S. (2020, April 26). Understanding what you feel: A Mobile Audio-Tactile System for Graphics Used at Schools with Students with Visual Impairment. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376508</span></li>
<li><span id="LangeHiveFive">of Oldenburg), D. L. (U., for IT), T. C. S. (O. F. F. I. S.- I., for IT), U. G. (O. F. F. I. S.- I., &amp; of Oldenburg), S. B. (U. (2020, April 26). HiveFive: Immersion Preserving Attention Guidance in Virtual Reality. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376803</span></li>
<li><span id="KoelleSocial">Marion Koelle (University of Oldenburg / Saarland University, S. I. C., of Oldenburg), S. A. (U., &amp; of Oldenburg), S. B. (U. (2020, April 26). Social Acceptability in HCI: A Survey of Methods, Measures, and Design Strategies. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376162</span></li>
<li><span id="KaulVibrotactile">Hannover), O. B. K. (L. U., Hannover), M. R. (L. U., Hannover), B. S. (L. U., Hannover), K. C. D. (L. U., &amp; Hannover), K. F. (L. U. (2020, April 26). Vibrotactile Funneling Illusion and Localization Performance on the Head. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376335</span></li>
<li><span id="KatsiniTheRole">Opsis), C. K. (H., Munich), Y. A. (B. U., Opsis), G. E. R. (H., of Glasgow), M. K. (U., &amp; Munich), F. A. (B. U. (2020, April 26). The Role of Eye Gaze in Security and Privacy Applications: Survey and Future HCI Research Directions. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376840</span></li>
<li><span id="MayerImproving">of Stuttgart), S. M. (C. M. U. / U., of Applied Sciences), J. R. (H. U., of Stuttgart), R. S. (U., College), B. J. (M., of Stuttgart / University of Regensburg), V. S. (U., of Applied Sciences), K. W. (H. U., &amp; of Regensburg), N. H. (U. (2020, April 26). Improving Humans’ Ability to Interpret Deictic Gestures in Virtual Reality. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376340</span></li>
<li><span id="KumarTagswipe">of Koblenz), C. K. (U., of Koblenz), R. H. (U., University), S. M. K. (Y., &amp; of Stuttgart), S. S. (U. (2020, April 26). TAGSwipe: Touch Assisted Gaze Swipe for Text Entry. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376317</span></li>
<li><span id="SenguptaLeveraging">of Koblenz), K. S. (U., of Koblenz), S. B. (U., of Tsukuba), S. S. (U., University), S. M. K. (Y., &amp; of Stuttgart), S. S. (U. (2020, April 26). Leveraging Error Correction in Voice-based Text Entry by Talk-and-Gaze. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376579</span></li>
<li><span id="KrausAssessing">of Konstanz), M. K. (U., of Stuttgart), K. A. (U., of Konstanz), J. B. (U., of Konstanz), D. S. (U., of Konstanz), D. K. (U., of Stuttgart), M. S. (U., &amp; of Konstanz), J. F. (U. (2020, April 26). Assessing 2D and 3D Heatmaps for Comparative Analysis: An Empirical Study. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376675</span></li>
<li><span id="SchubhanInvestigating">Marc Schubhan (German Research Center for Artificial Intelligence (DFKI), S. I. C., Maximilian Altmeyer (German Research Center for Artificial Intelligence (DFKI), S. I. C., University), D. B. (S., &amp; Pascal Lessel (German Research Center for Artificial Intelligence (DFKI), S. I. C. (2020, April 26). Investigating User-Created Gamification in an Image Tagging Task. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376360</span></li>
<li><span id="SchneegassBrainCode">Munich), C. S. (L. M. U., Munich), T. K. (L. M. U., Munich), A. B. (L. M. U., Munich), M. R. (L. M. U., Munich), M. H. (B. U., &amp; Munich), H. H. (L. M. U. (2020, April 26). BrainCoDe: Electroencephalography-based Comprehension Detection during Reading and Listening. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376707</span></li>
<li><span id="HoppeAHumanTouch">Munich), M. H. (L. M. U., Munich), B. R. (L. M. U., Munich), D. P. N. (L. M. U., of Konstanz), S. S. (U., Munich), A. S. (L. M. U., &amp; Munich), T. M. (L. M. U. (2020, April 26). A Human Touch: Social Touch Increases the Perceived Human-likeness of Agents in Virtual Reality. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376719</span></li>
<li><span id="KoschRSVP">Munich), T. K. (L. M. U., Munich), A. S. (L. M. U., Munich), S. T. (L. M. U., &amp; Munich), L. L. C. (L. M. U. (2020, April 26). One does not Simply RSVP: Mental Workload to Select Speed Reading Parameters using Electroencephalography. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376766</span></li>
<li><span id="VilleVirtual">University), V. M. (L. M. U. M. / T., Munich), R. R. (B. U., in Cairo), S. A. (G. U., of Glasgow), M. K. (U., Munich), C. X. (L. M. U., Munich), L. B. (L. M. U., Munich), A. S. (L. M. U., &amp; Munich), F. A. (B. U. (2020, April 26). Virtual Field Studies: Conducting Studies on Public Displays in Virtual Reality. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376796</span></li>
<li><span id="VoelkelHow">Munich), S. T. V. (L. M. U., Institute), R. H. (M. I. T., Munich), A. W. (L. M. U., Munich), H. H. (L. M. U., &amp; Munich), A. B. (L. M. U. (2020, April 26). How to Trick AI: Users’ Strategies for Protecting Themselves From Automatic Personality Assessment. <i>Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376877</span></li></ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Siegen), F. C. (U., Siegen), J. M. (U., Siegen), D. L. (U., Siegen), D. U. (U., Siegen), S. M. (U., Siegen), I. K. (U., Siegen), R. W. (U., Siegen), D. R. (U., Siegen), M. H. (U., &amp; Siegen), V. W. (U. (2020, May 1). Exploring Human-Robot Interaction with the Elderly: Results from a Ten-Week Case Study in a Care Home. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376402 University), Y. K. M. (S., College), X.-D. Y. (D., University), M. L. (A., University), M. C. (S., of Regensburg), N. H. (U., Research), S. H. (M., University), M. J. (S., of Technolgy), N. A. (G. I., &amp; of Technology), G. D. A. (G. I. (2020). SelfSustainableCHI: Self-Powered Sustainable Interfaces and Interactions. In Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. ACM. https://doi.org/10.1145/3334480.3375167 of Technology), A. K. (C. U., of Technology), A. B. (C. U., of Technology), S. T. (C. U., of Technology), M. S. (C. U., of Technology), M. E. (C. U., of Technology), M. B. (Q. U., &amp; of Applied Sciences), A. B. (A. U. (2020, May 1). Guess the Data: Data Work to Understand How People Make Sense of and Use Simple Sensor Data from Homes. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376273 Dresden), K. K. (T. U., Dresden), T. H. (T. U., &amp; Dresden), R. D. (T. U. (2020, April 26). Watch+Strap: Extending Smartwatches with Interactive StrapDisplays. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376199 Dresden), K. K. (T. U., Dresden), R. D. (T. U., &amp; University), J. S. (S. (2020, April 26). Rapid Iron-On User Interfaces: Hands-on Fabrication of Interactive Textile Prototypes. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376220 of Konstanz), M. D. (U., of Konstanz), C. G. (U., of Konstanz), U. P. (U., &amp; of Konstanz), H. R. (U. (2020, April 26). NurseCare: Design and ‘In-The-Wild’ Evaluation of a Mobile System to Promote the Ergonomic Transfer of Patients. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376851 University), F. ’F. M. (M., of Chicago), P. L. (U., of Copenhagen / Saarland University), P. S. (U., Tech), W. J. (C., University), C. S. (S., Europe), M. W. (H. R. I., of Auckland), S. N. (U., of Essex), M. O. (U., University), Z. L. (M., University), J. D. (M., of Chicago), J. N. (U., University), E. M. G. (N., of Copenhagen), D. S. (N. T. N. U. / I. T. U., (Microsoft), J. G., University), S. G. (D., University), K. K. (K., researcher), T. E. (I., Technologies), S. G. (C. A., of Tokyo), M. I. (U., … Lab), P. M. (M. I. T. M. (2020, April 26). Next Steps in Human-Computer Integration. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376242 of Konstanz), J. Z. (U., of Konstanz), U. P. (U., von Bauer (University of Konstanz), P., of Konstanz), D. F. (U., &amp; of Konstanz), H. R. (U. (2020, April 26). ’It’s in my other hand!’ - Studying the Interplay of Interaction Techniques and Multi-Tablet Activities. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376540 of Bremen), J. P. (U., University), J. D. S. (N., of Bremen), I. B. (U., &amp; of Bremen), R. M. (U. (2020, April 26). Bot or not? User Perceptions of Player Substitution with Deep Player Behavior Models. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376223 of Bremen), J. P. (U., University), J. D. S. (N., &amp; of Bremen), R. M. (U. (2020, April 26). Enemy Within: Long-term Motivation Effects of Deep Player Behavior Models for Dynamic Difficulty Adjustment. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376423 of Bremen), S. P. (U., of Bremen), D. A. (U., of Bremen), F. P. (U., of Bremen), S. H. (U., University), J. D. S. (N., &amp; of Bremen), R. M. (U. (2020, April 26). Breaking The Experience: Effects of Questionnaires in VR User Studies. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376144 of Bremen), D. A. (U., of Bremen), S. P. (U., of Bremen), M. B. (U., of Bremen), S. H. (U., of Bremen), P. M. (U., of Bremen), D. W. (U., of Bremen), R. M. (U., &amp; University), J. D. S. (N. (2020, April 26). Examining Design Choices of Questionnaires in VR User Studies. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376260 of Bremen), C. S. (U., of Bremen), S. M. K. A. Z. (U., of Bremen), M. H. U. P. (U., of Bremen), S. M. (U., &amp; of Bremen), G. Z. (U. (2020, April 26). Robustness of Eye Movement Biometrics Against Varying Stimuli and Varying Trajectory Length. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376534 of Bremen), F. P. (U., of Bremen), T. I. (U., of Bremen), T. S. (U., &amp; University), W. S. (S. F. (2020, April 26). Platform for Studying Self-Repairing Auto-Corrections in Mobile Text Entry based on Brain Activity, Gaze, and Context. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376815 of Saskatchewan), J. F. (U. U. / U., of Saskatchewan), V. S. (U., of Saskatchewan), A. E. D. (U., of Saskatchewan), C. J. (U., of Saskatchewan), M. K. M. (U., &amp; of Saskatchewan), R. L. M. (U. (2020, April 26). Recognizing Affiliation: Using Behavioural Traces to Predict the Quality of Social Interactions in Online Games. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376446 University), D. W. (U., University), J. G. (U., University), M. C. (U., &amp; University), E. R. (U. (2020, April 26). Understanding the Heisenberg Effect of Spatial Interaction: A Selection Induced Error for Spatially Tracked Input Devices. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376876 University), D. W. (U., University), K. R. (U., University), C. K. (U., &amp; University), E. R. (U. (2020, April 26). JumpVR: Jump-Based Locomotion Augmentation for Virtual Reality. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376243 University), E. S. (U., University), T. W. (U., University), J. G. (U., &amp; University), E. R. (U. (2020, April 26). Mix&amp;Match: Towards Omitting Modelling through In-Situ Alteration and Remixing of Model Repository Artifacts in Mixed Reality. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376839 University), M. C. (U., University), M. W. (U., University), J. G. (U., University), A. A. (U., &amp; University), E. R. (U. (2020, April 26). Towards Inclusive External Communication of Autonomous Vehicles for Pedestrians with Vision Impairments. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376472 University), T. D. (U., University), J. G. (U., University), J. K. (U., University), M. M. (U., &amp; University), E. R. (U. (2020, April 26). VRSketchIn: Exploring the Design Space of Pen and Tablet Interaction for 3D Sketching in Virtual Reality. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376628 University), M. R. (U., University), M. D. (U., University), T. D. (U., &amp; University), E. R. (U. (2020, April 26). Telewalk: Towards Free and Endless Walking in Room-Scale Virtual Reality. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376821 Clausthal), N. O. (T. U., &amp; Clausthal), M. P. (T. U. (2020, April 26). Getting out of Out of Sight: Evaluation of AR Mechanisms for Awareness and Orientation Support in Occluded Multi-Room Settings. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376742 OWL), S. B. (T. U. C. / T. H., Clausthal), M. P. (T. U., &amp; OWL), C. R. (T. H. (2020, April 26). Augmented Reality Training for Industrial Assembly Work – Are Projection-based AR Assistive Systems an Appropriate Tool for Assembly Training? Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376720 (RWTH), K. S., (RWTH), J. M., &amp; (RWTH), J. B. (2020, April 26). TRACTUS: Understanding and Supporting Source Code Experimentation in Hypothesis-Driven Data Science. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376764 (RWTH), P. W., (RWTH), A. W., (RWTH), S. V., &amp; (RWTH), J. B. (2020, April 26). Heatmaps, Shadows, Bubbles, Rays: Comparing Mid-Air Pen Position Visualizations in Handheld AR. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376848 (RWTH), S. V., (RWTH), S. H., Zurich), C. H. (E. T. H., University), C. R. (A., &amp; London), N. M. (U. C. (2020, April 26). GazeConduits: Calibration-Free Cross-Device Collaboration through Gaze and Touch. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376578 (RWTH), S. V., (RWTH), S. H., (RWTH), C. C., &amp; University), C. R. (A. (2020, April 26). HeadReach: Using Head Tracking to Increase Reachability on Mobile Touch Devices. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376868 Darmstadt), K. M. (T. U., Darmstadt), M. S. (T. U., Darmstadt), V. Z. (T. U., Darmstadt), M. H. (T. U., Design), K. K. (K. M., &amp; Darmstadt), M. M. (T. U. (2020, April 26). 3D-Auth: Two-Factor Authentication with Personalized 3D-Printed Items. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376189 von Willich (TU Darmstadt), J., Darmstadt), M. S. (T. U., Darmstadt), F. M. (T. U., Darmstadt), D. S. (T. U., &amp; Darmstadt), M. M. (T. U. (2020, April 26). Podoportation: Foot-Based Locomotion in Virtual Reality. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376626 Darmstadt), K. M. (T. U., Darmstadt), V. Z. (T. U., GmbH), M. F. (C., Darmstadt), J. D. (T. U., Darmstadt), K. B. (T. U., &amp; Darmstadt), M. M. (T. U. (2020, April 26). Improving the Usability and UX of the Swiss Internet Voting Interface. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376769 Darmstadt), S. G. (T. U., Darmstadt), F. M. (T. U., Darmstadt), D. S. (T. U., (GUC), O. E., Darmstadt), M. S. (T. U., &amp; Darmstadt), M. M. (T. U. (2020, April 26). Therminator: Understanding the Interdependency of Visual and On-Body Thermal Feedback in Virtual Reality. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376195 Darmstadt), F. M. (T. U., Darmstadt), M. S. (T. U., Darmstadt), D. S. (T. U., Darmstadt), S. G. (T. U., Darmstadt), M. F. (T. U., &amp; Darmstadt), M. M. (T. U. (2020, April 26). Walk The Line: Leveraging Lateral Shifts of the Walking Path as an Input Modality for Head-Mounted Displays. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376852 Hamburg), F. M. (U., Hamburg), F. S. (U., Hamburg), O. A. (U., of Ioannina), D. G. (U., &amp; of Ioannina), D. F. (U. (2020, April 26). Augmented Reality for Older Adults: Exploring Acceptability of Virtual Coaches for Home-based Balance Training in an Aging Population. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376565 Hamburg), J. P. F. (U., Hamburg), O. A. (U., Hamburg), O. J. (U., &amp; Hamburg), F. S. (U. (2020, April 26). Walking by Cycling: A Novel In-Place Locomotion User Interface for Seated Virtual Reality Experiences. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376574 Siegen), D. U. (U., Siegen), K. A. (U., Bonn-Rhein-Siegen), D. D. V. (H., Siegen), P. D. T. (U., Siegen), R. W. (U., Siegen), D. R. (U., &amp; Siegen), V. W. (U. (2020, April 26). Social Technology Appropriation in Dementia: Investigating the Role of Caregivers in engaging People with Dementia with a Videogame-based Training System. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376648 Siegen), M. L. (U., Healthineers), C. B. (S., Siegen), R. N. (U., &amp; Siegen), M. H. (U. (2020, April 26). Meaningful Technology at Work – A Reflective Design Case of Improving Radiologists’ Wellbeing Through Medical Technology. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376710 Siegen), A. U. (U., GmbH), N. S. (E., GmbH), D. P. W. (E., &amp; Siegen), M. H. (U. (2020, April 26). Fairness and Decision-making in Collaborative Shift Scheduling Systems. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376656 (KIT-SZS), G. M., (KIT-SZS), K. M., (KIT-SZS), T. S., (KIT-SZS), G. J., &amp; (KIT-SZS), R. S. (2020, April 26). Understanding what you feel: A Mobile Audio-Tactile System for Graphics Used at Schools with Students with Visual Impairment. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376508 of Oldenburg), D. L. (U., for IT), T. C. S. (O. F. F. I. S.- I., for IT), U. G. (O. F. F. I. S.- I., &amp; of Oldenburg), S. B. (U. (2020, April 26). HiveFive: Immersion Preserving Attention Guidance in Virtual Reality. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376803 Marion Koelle (University of Oldenburg / Saarland University, S. I. C., of Oldenburg), S. A. (U., &amp; of Oldenburg), S. B. (U. (2020, April 26). Social Acceptability in HCI: A Survey of Methods, Measures, and Design Strategies. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376162 Hannover), O. B. K. (L. U., Hannover), M. R. (L. U., Hannover), B. S. (L. U., Hannover), K. C. D. (L. U., &amp; Hannover), K. F. (L. U. (2020, April 26). Vibrotactile Funneling Illusion and Localization Performance on the Head. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376335 Opsis), C. K. (H., Munich), Y. A. (B. U., Opsis), G. E. R. (H., of Glasgow), M. K. (U., &amp; Munich), F. A. (B. U. (2020, April 26). The Role of Eye Gaze in Security and Privacy Applications: Survey and Future HCI Research Directions. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376840 of Stuttgart), S. M. (C. M. U. / U., of Applied Sciences), J. R. (H. U., of Stuttgart), R. S. (U., College), B. J. (M., of Stuttgart / University of Regensburg), V. S. (U., of Applied Sciences), K. W. (H. U., &amp; of Regensburg), N. H. (U. (2020, April 26). Improving Humans’ Ability to Interpret Deictic Gestures in Virtual Reality. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376340 of Koblenz), C. K. (U., of Koblenz), R. H. (U., University), S. M. K. (Y., &amp; of Stuttgart), S. S. (U. (2020, April 26). TAGSwipe: Touch Assisted Gaze Swipe for Text Entry. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376317 of Koblenz), K. S. (U., of Koblenz), S. B. (U., of Tsukuba), S. S. (U., University), S. M. K. (Y., &amp; of Stuttgart), S. S. (U. (2020, April 26). Leveraging Error Correction in Voice-based Text Entry by Talk-and-Gaze. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376579 of Konstanz), M. K. (U., of Stuttgart), K. A. (U., of Konstanz), J. B. (U., of Konstanz), D. S. (U., of Konstanz), D. K. (U., of Stuttgart), M. S. (U., &amp; of Konstanz), J. F. (U. (2020, April 26). Assessing 2D and 3D Heatmaps for Comparative Analysis: An Empirical Study. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376675 Marc Schubhan (German Research Center for Artificial Intelligence (DFKI), S. I. C., Maximilian Altmeyer (German Research Center for Artificial Intelligence (DFKI), S. I. C., University), D. B. (S., &amp; Pascal Lessel (German Research Center for Artificial Intelligence (DFKI), S. I. C. (2020, April 26). Investigating User-Created Gamification in an Image Tagging Task. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376360 Munich), C. S. (L. M. U., Munich), T. K. (L. M. U., Munich), A. B. (L. M. U., Munich), M. R. (L. M. U., Munich), M. H. (B. U., &amp; Munich), H. H. (L. M. U. (2020, April 26). BrainCoDe: Electroencephalography-based Comprehension Detection during Reading and Listening. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376707 Munich), M. H. (L. M. U., Munich), B. R. (L. M. U., Munich), D. P. N. (L. M. U., of Konstanz), S. S. (U., Munich), A. S. (L. M. U., &amp; Munich), T. M. (L. M. U. (2020, April 26). A Human Touch: Social Touch Increases the Perceived Human-likeness of Agents in Virtual Reality. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376719 Munich), T. K. (L. M. U., Munich), A. S. (L. M. U., Munich), S. T. (L. M. U., &amp; Munich), L. L. C. (L. M. U. (2020, April 26). One does not Simply RSVP: Mental Workload to Select Speed Reading Parameters using Electroencephalography. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376766 University), V. M. (L. M. U. M. / T., Munich), R. R. (B. U., in Cairo), S. A. (G. U., of Glasgow), M. K. (U., Munich), C. X. (L. M. U., Munich), L. B. (L. M. U., Munich), A. S. (L. M. U., &amp; Munich), F. A. (B. U. (2020, April 26). Virtual Field Studies: Conducting Studies on Public Displays in Virtual Reality. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376796 Munich), S. T. V. (L. M. U., Institute), R. H. (M. I. T., Munich), A. W. (L. M. U., Munich), H. H. (L. M. U., &amp; Munich), A. B. (L. M. U. (2020, April 26). How to Trick AI: Users’ Strategies for Protecting Themselves From Automatic Personality Assessment. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI 2020. https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376877]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Contributing German HCI Labs 2020</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/maps/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Contributing German HCI Labs 2020" /><published>2023-03-01T15:56:47+01:00</published><updated>2023-03-01T15:56:47+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021%20-%20Copy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/maps/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/images/map.svg" alt="Descripción de la imagen" /></p>

<h2 id="rwth-aachen-university">RWTH Aachen University</h2>
<h3 id="media-computing-group">Media Computing Group</h3>
<p>Jan Borchers – hci.rwth-aachen.de</p>

<p>At the Media Computing Group, headed by Prof. Dr. Jan Borchers, we work in Human-Computer Interaction. We develop and study new interaction theories, techniques, and systems in areas like personal digital fabrication and personal design, tangible, mobile, and wearable user interfaces, interactive textiles, multitouch tables and interactive surfaces, augmented reality, and visual coding environments. Our goal is to make the Brave New World of interactive technologies useful by making it usable. Since starting in October 2003, we have become one of Germany’s best-published research groups at CHI, the premier international academic conference in the field.</p>

<h2 id="universität-bremen">Universität Bremen</h2>
<h3 id="digital-media-lab-tzi">Digital Media Lab, TZI</h3>
<p>Rainer Malaka – tzi.de</p>
<h3 id="cgvr-tzi">CGVR, TZI</h3>
<p>Gabriel Zachmann – tzi.de</p>

<p>The Center for Computing Technologies (TZI) at the University of Bremen conducts research at the core of a massive societal trend: The digital revolution, which affects all areas of our lives. Important research questions include: What kind of technologies will we have in 10 to 20 years? How can we make sure that they will be safe, dependable, and beneficial for society? And most of all: How can technology serve humans–instead of replacing them? TZI has conducted research in these areas since its foundation in 1995, working on approximately 120 projects per year. One main goal is to transfer results from basic research to industry as quickly as possible in order to generate the greatest benefits for society.</p>

<h2 id="tu-chemnitz">TU Chemnitz</h2>
<h3 id="medieninformatik">Medieninformatik</h3>
<p>Maximilian Eibl – http://www.tu-chemnitz.de/informatik/mi</p>

<p>The chair media informatics at TU Chemnitz does research and teaching in Human Computer Interaction, Multimedia Information Retrieval, and Media Distribution.</p>

<h2 id="clausthal-university-of-technology">Clausthal University of Technology</h2>
<h3 id="human-centred-information-systems">Human-Centred Information Systems</h3>
<p>Michael Prilla – http://hcis.in.tu-clausthal.de/</p>

<p>We investigate the work, learning and behavior of people in order to support them with IT tools. In this we focus on the practice of people, which includes multiple (individual) factors and constraints that shape the way people act and develops of time an constantly. IT is then one factor that influences work, and the understanding of all other factors enables us to support individuals and group appropriately. Our work includes individuals (human computer interaction) as well as support for groups (computer supported cooperative work and collaborative learning).</p>

<h2 id="tu-darmstadt">TU Darmstadt</h2>
<h3 id="telecooperation-lab">Telecooperation Lab</h3>
<p>Max Mühlhäuser – www.teamdarmstadt.de</p>

<p>The Telecooperation Lab (TK) under the supervision of Prof. Max Mühlhäuser at Darmstadt Technical University, Department of Computer Science, researches concepts and methods for human-centered smart spaces of all sizes where telecooperation means targeted cooperation among humans and machines, based on information &amp; communication technology. At the HCI group of the Telecooperation Lab, we investigate and study novel interaction concepts and techniques in the research fields that cover Fabrication, Augmented and Virtual Reality, Interactive Surfaces, On-body Haptics, Usable Security and Assisting Technology for children and people with special needs.</p>

<h2 id="technische-universität-dresden">Technische Universität Dresden</h2>
<h3 id="interactive-media-lab">Interactive Media Lab</h3>
<p>Prof. Dr. Raimund Dachselt – http://imld.de</p>

<p>The Interactive Media Lab at the Technische Universität Dresden is conducting research primarily in the field of modern Human-Computer Interaction and interactive Information Visualization. Our main focus are natural user interfaces, in particular the development of interaction techniques and data visualization approaches using various interaction modalities (multitouch, pen, gaze, tangibles, gestures) and their combination. Typical research setups are multi-display and Mixed Reality environments as well as wearables for augmenting humans. We apply our basic research results to several application domains, like biology, medicine and cyber-physical systems, and develop domain-specific solutions.</p>

<h2 id="university-of-duisburg-essen">University of Duisburg-Essen</h2>
<h3 id="paluno-hci-group">paluno, HCI Group</h3>
<p>Stefan Schneegass – www.hci.wiwi.uni-due.de</p>

<p>The HCI Group at the University of Duisburg-Essen (Campus Essen) is a part of paluno, the The Ruhr Institute for Software Technology. Our research focuses on the domains of immersive VR/MR, automotive UIs, Human-Robot interaction and usable security &amp; privacy. We are also delighted to host the 19th International Conference on Mobile and Ubiquitous Multimedia (MUM) this year and welcome the HCI community to Essen.</p>

<h2 id="universität-hamburg">Universität Hamburg</h2>
<h3 id="human-computer-interaction">Human-Computer Interaction</h3>
<p>Frank Steinicke – www.inf.uni-hamburg.de/en/inst/ab/hci.html</p>

<p>The Human-Computer Interaction (HC) research group is part of the Department of Informatics at the Faulty of Mathematics, Informatics and Natural Sciences at the Universität Hamburg (UHH). Our group is particularly interested in developing innovative user interfaces for computer-mediated blended realities in which the two-dimensional digital world and intelligence meets human intelligence and the three-dimensional physical world we live in. In our group we combine methods from computer science (software development, in particular computer graphics and artificial intelligence), engineering (hardware prototyping, in particular with sensors and actuators for novel user interface technology) and basic principles and models of psychology (such as perception, cognition or action) as well as interaction design (e.g. usability and user experience engineering) to reform the future interaction between humans and technology. The results advance the state-of-the-art in basic research, applied research, and experimental development in the area of augmented/virtual reality, virtual agents and avatars, and 3D user interfaces as well as spatial user interaction. The results can be applied in a variety of application domains such as health, simulation, training, communication, entertainment, education or training.</p>

<h2 id="leibniz-universität-hannover">Leibniz Universität Hannover</h2>
<h3 id="human-computer-interaction-group">Human-Computer Interaction Group</h3>
<p>Michael Rohs – hci.uni-hannover.de</p>

<p>The Human-Computer Interaction Group is part of the Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science at Leibniz University Hannover. Our research and teaching focuses on the design, implementation, and evaluation of mobile, wearable, and ubiquitous interactive systems. Current topics include the application of machine learning techniques in sensor-based mobile interactions and mobile haptic feedback, e.g. for pedestrian navigation and visually impaired people.</p>

<h2 id="technische-hochschule-ingolstadt-thi">Technische Hochschule Ingolstadt (THI)</h2>
<h3 id="human-computer-interaction-group-1">Human-Computer Interaction Group</h3>
<p>Andreas Riener – hcig.thi.de</p>

<p>The Human-Computer Interaction Group (HCIG) at THI, headed by Prof. Andreas Riener, is an interdisciplinary team with particular focus on usability research for intelligent user interfaces and user experience design. The research group is interested in augmented, mixed, and virtual reality applications to study novel and efficient interaction metaphors, motion/simulator sickness, trust/acceptance of technology, and usability/UX of (adaptive) interfaces. The group’s particular interest lies in the automotive domain, with prototypes/systems evaluated in driving simulator studies, lab experiments and in the field. The research agenda of the HCIG can be expressed as the “development of future interaction concepts and intelligent user interfaces that include cognitive elements to reflect the uniqueness of its users”.</p>

<h2 id="karlsruhe-institute-of-technology-kit">Karlsruhe Institute of Technology (KIT)</h2>
<h3 id="study-centre-for-the-visually-impaired-szs">Study Centre for the Visually Impaired (SZS)</h3>
<p>Computer Vision for Human-Computer Interaction Lab
Rainer Stiefelhagen – www.szs.kit.edu</p>

<p>The Study Centre for the Visually Impaired (SZS) is part of the Faculty of Computer Science at the Karlsruhe Institute of Technology (KIT). The SZS supports and advises visually impaired students and prospective students in all study courses offered at KIT. The work of the SZS aims at continuously developing innovative and individual solutions for accessible studies, especially in STEM (science, technologies, engineering and informatics) fields. Thereby, students with blindness or low vision get the opportunity to study in a self-determined and inclusive way at KIT and to find access to professional life. Moreover, the SZS does research on Assistive Technologies and on new ways of getting access to STEM fields together with the Computer Vision for Human-Computer Interaction Lab (cv:hci) which are both directed by Prof. Rainer Stiefelhagen.</p>

<h2 id="university-of-konstanz">University of Konstanz</h2>
<h3 id="hci-group">HCI Group</h3>
<p>Harald Reiterer – hci.uni-konstanz.de/</p>

<p>Harald Reiterer’s HCI Group is part of the Department of Computer and Information Science at the University of Konstanz, which is one of the eleven Universities of Excellence in Germany. Our group designs individual and collaborative user interfaces using virtual and augmented realities to ubiquitous computing systems while following our vision of “Blended Interaction.” Based on embodiment theory, Blended Interaction describes the successful blend of physically embodied interaction and computational power. Our research and teaching unify the areas of human-computer interaction, information visualization, and usability engineering. We integrate user-centred design and traditional engineering methods into our research philosophy. Typically, we define our research around realistic application scenarios in close cooperation with domain experts from areas such as visual computing, psychology, or healthcare. Together with our partners, we seek to identify the real needs of practitioners and then design and implement innovative user interfaces that live up to real-world requirements.</p>

<h2 id="hochschule-anhalt-köthen">Hochschule Anhalt (Köthen)</h2>
<h3 id="professor-for-hci">Professor for HCI</h3>
<p>Arne Berger – www.hs-anhalt.de/hochschule-anhalt/service/personenverzeichnis/ prof-dr-arne-berger.html</p>

<p>I am a full professor for Human-Computer-Interaction at Hochschule Anhalt. I work at the intersection of creating future technology and our responsibility for the unintended side-effects of yesterday’s technology.</p>

<h2 id="lmu-munich">LMU Munich</h2>
<h3 id="media-informatics-group">Media Informatics Group</h3>
<p>Andreas Butz – www.mimuc.de</p>

<p>Heinrich Hußmann – www.mimuc.de</p>

<p>Albrecht Schmidt – ubicomp.net</p>

<p>At LMU Munich, three groups are working closely together in HCI research under the general title “Media Informatics”. All three groups conduct research on the crossroads of human behavior and machine computation. This comprises a broad range of topics, including novel interfaces and interaction technologies, development methodologies, and application case studies – always with a human-centered focus.
The core Media Informatics group (Heinrich Hußmann) focuses on methods for smooth transitions along the mixed reality continuum, on the application of physical sensing methods to improve interaction and learning, and on interdisciplinary research in the interaction between humans and intelligent assistants. An important application area is the automotive domain.
Research in the LMU HCI group (Andreas Butz) centers around the idea of mixing the digital and the physical world. This includes Ubiquitous Computing environments in the classical sense, be they living rooms, handball courts, or the public space, but also our interaction with autonomous cars and robots, and generally the interplay between human and artificial intelligence.
The Human-Centered Ubiquitous Media group (Albrecht Schmidt) explores digital technologies that allow augmenting and amplifying human cognition and perception. The focus is on experimental research aiming at designing and implementing human-centered intelligent interactive systems. Technically this includes work on physiological user interfaces, augmented and virtual reality, and novel input and output channels.</p>

<h2 id="bundeswehr-university-munich">Bundeswehr University Munich</h2>
<h3 id="usable-security-and-privacy-group-research-institute-code">Usable Security and Privacy Group, Research Institute CODE</h3>
<p>Florian Alt – www.unibw.de/usable-security-and-privacy</p>

<p>The Usable Security and Privacy Group is part of the Research Institute CODE at the Bundeswehr University Munich. The group is headed by Prof. Florian Alt.</p>

<p>We explore the design of secure systems that blend with the way in which users interact with computing devices. In particular, our research focuses on understanding users’ behavior in security critical contexts, in building security mechanisms based on users’ behavior (behavioral biometrics), in leveraging users’ physiology to both enhance existing security mechanisms as well as build novel security mechanisms (physiological security) and in understanding and investigating threats that emerge from novel ubiquitous technologies (ubiquitous security). Specific application areas are smart homes, social engineering and virtual reality.</p>

<p>In the context of our research we employ and enhance methods commonly known from Human-Computer Interaction. These include but are not limited to user-centered design and iterative prototyping. Our work is strongly centered around humans, making empirical approaches a fundamental part of our research. To understand behavior as well as to evaluate novel approaches, we conduct studies in the lab and in the field.</p>

<p>The group has won best paper and honorable mention awards at CHI, MobileHCI, IDC, and AmI. The research has been funded by the DFG, the ZD.B / Bavarian State Ministry for Education and Science, BMW, the Humboldt Foundation, the DAAD, Google, and the Telekom Innovation Labs.</p>

<h2 id="university-of-oldenburg">University of Oldenburg</h2>
<h3 id="medieninformatik-1">Medieninformatik</h3>
<p>Susanne Boll – uol.de/en/media-informatics</p>

<p>The Media Informatics and Multimedia Systems Group is working in the fields of Human Computer Interaction. We develop interactive systems and computing technologies to enhance users’ lives. We focus primarily on mobile and ambient user interfaces, where we explore different novel modalities such as visual, auditory and tactile channels in pervasive displays. We strongly embed our research in the fields of personal health and safe transportation, that serve as major application domains. The group is headed by Prof. Dr. Susanne Boll. She is leading several national and international scientific projects with strong cooperation with research experts world wide. She head one of the few leading groups in Europe that works on mobile and ambient user interfaces exploring different novel modalities such as visual, auditory and tactile in pervasive displays. The research groups makes competitive contributions to the field of human computer interaction and ubiquitous computing. The research projects also have a strong connection to industry partners and application partners and addresses highly relevant challenges in the applications field of automation in transportation systems as well as health care technologies.</p>

<h2 id="offis--institute-for-information-technology-oldenburg">OFFIS – Institute for Information Technology (Oldenburg)</h2>
<h3 id="interactive-systems-group">Interactive Systems Group</h3>
<p>Susanne Boll – www.offis.de</p>

<p>OFFIS Interactive Systems Group develops interactive systems and computing technologies to enhance users’ lives. We focus primarily on mobile and ambient user interfaces, where we explore different novel modalities such as visual, auditory and tactile channels in pervasive displays. We strongly embed our research in the fields of personal health and safe transportation, that serve as major application domains.</p>

<h2 id="university-of-regensburg">University of Regensburg</h2>
<h3 id="medieninformatik--interaction-lab">Medieninformatik – Interaction Lab</h3>
<p>Niels Henze – interactionlab.io | mi.uni-regensburg.de</p>

<p>The Chair of Media Informatics is the part of the Institute for Information and Media, Language and Culture at the University of Regensburg. We are interested in how users use computers today and how they will use them in the future. We develop interaction techniques, interactive systems, and applications that change the way users perceive and capture information. We investigate human perception and cognitive processes to understand how future technologies should be designed. Our research areas include mobile interactive systems, virtual, augmented and mixed reality, interactive systems for cultural heritage, and machine learning.</p>

<h2 id="saarland-university">Saarland University</h2>
<h3 id="ubiquitous-media-technology-lab-german-research-center-for-artificial-intelligence-dfki">Ubiquitous Media Technology Lab, German Research Center for Artificial Intelligence (DFKI)</h3>
<p>Antonio Krüger – umtl.cs.uni-saarland.de</p>

<p>Agents and Simulated Reality, German Research Center for Artificial Intelligence (DFKI)
Philipp Slusallek – graphics.cg.uni-saarland.de</p>

<p>The Ubiquitous Media Technologies Lab (UMTL) is part of the Saarland Informatics Campus and the Cognitive Assistants department (COS) at the German Research Center for Artificial Intelligence (DFKI). Our research activities focus on human factors in interactive systems, in particular, in the fields of multi-modal interaction, ubiquitous computing and gaming. Our research areas include augmented &amp; virtual reality, assistive technologies in health &amp; sports, gamification &amp; games user research, human-robot interaction &amp; collaboration, interactive &amp; applied machine learning, mobile &amp; wearable computing and usable privacy &amp; security. We publish our research findings at renowned scientific conferences and apply our results in the retail domain in our living lab called the Innovative Retail Laboratory. Through our activities in the study program Media Informatics at Saarland University, we contribute to the education of the next generation of HCI practitioners and researchers. We offer lectures, courses, media projects, Bachelor’s &amp; Master’s theses and an engaging work environment in which interactive systems are designed, prototyped, fabricated &amp; evaluated.</p>

<h3 id="hci-lab">HCI Lab</h3>
<p>Jürgen Steimle – hci.cs.uni-saarland.de</p>

<p>Our research mission is to contribute toward a future of embodied user interfaces that merge seamlessly with the physical world and with the human body, creating more effective, expressive and engaging interactions with interactive systems. In our work, we conceive new principles for interaction and novel interaction techniques; we develop user interface technologies for advanced sensing and display; we contribute design and fabrication tools for rapid prototyping of embodied user interfaces; and we model and empirically investigate user behavior with these interfaces. Embodied interaction has manifold applications in diverse areas, including consumer electronics, mobile computing, wearable computing, robotics, smart home, health and fitness devices.</p>

<h2 id="university-of-siegen">University of Siegen</h2>
<h3 id="information-systems-and-new-media">Information Systems and New Media</h3>
<p>Volker Wulf – www.wineme.uni-siegen.de</p>

<p>Information and communications technology (ICT) pervades most aspects of our lives and changes everyday’s practices in work and leisure time. To design innovative ICTs we need to engage with practices, institutional arrangements, and technological infrastructures. All of these issues are interrelated and historical grown, they need appropriate design methods. The challenge in the field of human-centred computing is to design innovative applications so that their appropriation leads to a better quality of life, sustainable development, and social integration. We are investigating into innovative ICTs, especially in the practice fields of cooperative work, community support, entertainment, ageing societies, and sustainability. In doing so, we contribute to the research fields of Human Computer Interaction, Computer Supported Cooperative Work, Ubiquitous Computing, and Software Engineering. The investigations into innovative ICTs in specific domains are related to each other via cross-cutting issues. These issues are currently ubiquitous and software technologies, methods of participatory design, end-user development, integration of organization and technology development, and the foundations of design science.</p>

<p>Computer Supported Cooperative Work and Social Media
Volkmar Pipek – www.cscw.uni-siegen.de</p>

<p>We are an interdisciplinary research group of the University of Siegen dealing with IT-supported cooperation between humans. Particularly we deal with questions of the arrangement and acquirement of cooperative software systems in organizations, questions about communication based knowledge management and also with the support of communities. The last topic involves questions of social structuring by and with information technology (for instance in the fields of E-democracy or in civil security). Computer-Supported Cooperative Work / CSCW is an interdisciplinary field of research which includes not only methodology and contents of Computer Science and Information Systems, but also disciplines of business administration, organizations theory, ergonomics, sociology, psychology and anthropology/ethnography. Seen from the view of Computer Science CSCW is a subarea of Information Systems and HCI (Human-Computer Interaction).</p>

<p>Experience &amp; Interaction Design
Marc Hassenzahl – www.experienceandinteraction.com</p>

<p>We explore design between the material and experiential, touching upon industrial, interaction and critical design.</p>

<p>Cyber-Physical Systems
Thomas Ludwig – cps.wineme.fb5.uni-siegen.de/en/</p>

<p>Our research group is engaged in research and teaching about the conception and design of cyber-physical systems, its technical development as well as its appropriation by users in different fields of application. Cyber-physical systems (CPS) describe the coupling of physical or biological components that can be integrated, observed and controlled via a computing unit. Essential components of cyber-physical systems are information and software technology components with mechanical or electronic components that communicate with each other via a communication infrastructure (e.g. the internet). Today, cyber-physical systems can be found wherever complex physical systems can be improved by communicating with the virtual, digital world. Examples are smart production facilities (industry 4.0) or e-health.</p>

<p>IT for the Ageing Society
Claudia Müller – www.wineme.uni-siegen.de/en/team/mueller/</p>

<p>It is common knowledge that demographic change gives rise to numerous challenges and problems. The teaching and research at the heart of the assistant Professorship are concerned with finding solutions to these issues; solutions which are supported by information technology. The aim is to maintain and improve the social inclusion of the elderly, particularly their mobility and independence, as well as to enable them to lead a comfortable, healthy life at home, even at an advanced age.</p>

<p>IT-Security and Consumer Computing
Gunnar Stevens – www.itsec.wiwi.uni-siegen.de</p>

<p>The Chair of Information Systems, in particular IT-Security and Consumer Computing researches the digital transformation of society from the consumer’s point of view with the aim of increasing digital sovereignty. The chair is located in the new research field of consumer informatics. Consumer informatics is the systematic, methodically guided investigation and design of information and communication technologies to support the household economies and everyday practices of consumers as well as their appropriation and social embedding. Consumer informatics thereby undergoes a change of perspective in which not only the role as a user of a system or customer of a company, but also the individual and collective life worlds of consumers are focused as comprehensively as possible.</p>

<p>Lab Logo
University of Stuttgart
Institute for Visualisation and Interactive Systems – Perceptual User Interfaces Group
Andreas Bulling – perceptualui.org</p>

<p>The Human-Computer Interaction and Cognitive Systems group focuses on developing next-generation human-machine interfaces that offer human-like perceptual, cognitive, and interactive capabilities. To this end we research fundamental computational methods as well as ambient and on-body systems to sense, model, and analyse everyday non-verbal human behaviour.</p>

<p>Institute for Parallel and Distributed Systems – Analytic Computing Group
Steffen Staab – www.ipvs.uni-stuttgart.de/departments/ac/</p>

<p>The group on Analytic Computing works on issues related to Artificial Intelligence (AI, Web, and Society; AI and HCI; KR and data bases) and Machine Learning (Machine Learning and Natural Language; Machine Learning and Sensing). The research group has been newly founded by Prof. Staab in 2020 as part of the Cyber Valley initiative of the local state of Baden-Württemberg. With this initiative the local region is supported by the state to become a major hub for AI. The group on Analytic Computing will comprise 12 researchers by the middle of 2020. It has already a range of projects running in the above-mentioned 5 project areas.</p>

<p>Institute for Visualisation and Interactive Systems – Visualization Research Center
Daniel Weiskopf | Michael Sedlmair – www.visus.uni-stuttgart.de/en/</p>

<p>At the Visualization Research Center 30 scientists research in different areas of scientific visualisation, visual analytics, visual computing and computer graphics, as well as interdisciplinary, applied research. The latter results in a very close co-operation with non-visualization disciplines of the University of Stuttgart.</p>

<p>Lab Logo
Ulm University
Institute of Media Informatics – Human-Computer-Interaction Group
Enrico Rukzio – www.uni-ulm.de/in/mi/</p>

<p>The Human-Computer-Interaction Group is located at the Institute of Media Informatics at Ulm University, and is headed by Enrico Rukzio. We are interested in designing intelligent interactive systems that enable people to be more efficient, satisfied and expressive in their daily lives. We design, implement (hard- and software) and evaluate novel interaction techniques, applications and services which either solve existing problems or provide new opportunities. Our research approach is based on design thinking, user centred design and iterative prototyping. At this, we involve potential users in all steps of the process, use a large body of low- and high-fidelity prototyping techniques and conduct a large number of user studies, evaluations and field tests. Our research focuses on the design of novel interaction concepts, devices and applications in areas such as mobile and wearable interaction, projected user interfaces, computerized eyewear, cross-device interactions, interaction in smart environments, human-technology interaction for elderly people, automotive user interfaces and interactive production planning.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">References 2021</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="References 2021" /><published>2023-03-01T15:56:47+01:00</published><updated>2023-03-01T15:56:47+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/"><![CDATA[<ol class="bibliography"><li><span id="Feich2021_Visuohaptic">Martin Feick (DFKI, S. I. C., Niko Kleer (DFKI, S. I. C., André Zenner (Saarland University &amp; DFKI, S. I. C., of Toronto), A. T. (U., &amp; Antonio Krüger (DFKI, S. I. C. (2021, May 8). <i>Visuo-haptic Illusions for Linear Translation and Stretching using Physical Proxies in Virtual Reality</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445456</span></li>
<li><span id="Zenner2021Hart">DFKI), A. Z. (S. U. &amp;, DFKI), H. M. K. (S. U. &amp;, &amp; DFKI), A. K. (S. U. &amp;. (2021, May 8). <i>HaRT - The Virtual Reality Hand Redirection Toolkit</i>. https://doi.org/0.1145/3411763.3451814</span></li>
<li><span id="2021WeberFoodInfluencers">Philip Weber (Cyber-Physical Systems, U. of S., Thomas Ludwig (Cyber-Physical Systems, U. of S., Sabrina Brodesser (Cyber-Physical Systems, U. of S., &amp; Laura Grönewald (Cyber-Physical Systems, U. of S. (2021, May 8). <i>“It’s a kind of art!”: Understanding Food Influencers as Influential Content Creators</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445607</span></li>
<li><span id="weizhuo2021document">Weizhou Luo (Interactive Media Lab Dresden, T. U. D., Anke Lehmann (Interactive Media Lab Dresden, T. U. D., Yushan Yang (Interactive Media Lab Dresden, T. U. D., &amp; Raimund Dachselt (Interactive Media Lab Dresden, T. U. D. (2021, May 7). <i>Investigating Document Layout and Placement Strategies for Collaborative Sensemaking in Augmented Reality</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451588</span></li>
<li><span id="Krueger2021CareRole">Siegen), M. K. (U., Siegen), A. W. (U., de Castro Leal (Universität Siegen), D., Siegen), D. R. (U., &amp; Siegen), V. W. (U. (2021, May 7). <i>It Takes More Than One Hand to Clap: On the Role of ‘Care’ in Maintaining Design Results</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445389</span></li>
<li><span id="Mouratidis2021ethnography">of Siegen), M. M. (U., of Siegen), S. R. (U., of Siegen), K. A. (U., University), N. B.-R. (R., Shaimaa Lazem (City of Scientifc Research, T. A., of Science, A. P. (N. U., Technology), S. H. (U. of C., University), V. V. (N., of Sussex), A. L. (U., of Siegen), D. R. (U., &amp; of Siegen), V. W. (U. (2021, May 7). <i>Coping with Messiness in Ethnography: Authority, Bias and Immersion in ethnographic Fieldwork in the non-Western World</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3441328</span></li>
<li><span id="Struzek2021Vulnerability"><i>Designing for New Forms of Vulnerability: Exploring transformation and empowerment in times of COVID-19</i>. (2021, May 7). https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3441339</span></li>
<li><span id="Schneegass2021LYLO">Munich), C. S. (L. M. U., Munich), D. I. (L. M. U., Munich), F. B. (L. M. U., &amp; of Bayreuth), D. B. (U. (2021, May 7). <i>LYLO – Exploring Disclosed Configurations for Inter-Personal Location Sharing</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451652</span></li>
<li><span id="Subramanian2021detectables">University), K. S. (R. W. T. H. A., University), J. M. (R. W. T. H. A., University), J. B. (R. W. T. H. A., &amp; and Jim Hollan (University of California, S. D. (2021, May 7). <i>From Detectables to Inspectables: Understanding Qualitative Analysis of Audiovisual Data</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445458​</span></li>
<li><span id="Mueller2021Spatial">Leon Müller (LMU Munich, G., Munich), K. P. (B. U., Institut, J. G. (T. P.- L. T. C. I., Polytechnique de Paris, F., Paris, Bastian Pfleging (Eindhoven University of Technology, N., Eindhoven, LMU Munich, G., Munich, Sarah Prange (Bundeswehr University Munich, G., Munich, LMU Munich, G., Munich, &amp; Florian Alt (Bundeswehr University Munich, G., Munich. (2021, May 7). <i>SpatialProto: Exploring Real-World Motion Captures for Rapid Prototyping of Interactive Mixed Reality</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445560</span></li>
<li><span id="2021TerzimehicUbiquitous">Munich), N. T. (L. M. U., Munich), C. G. (L. M. U., of Freiburg), R. H. (U., &amp; Munich), H. H. (L. M. U. (2021, May 7). <i>On Ubiquitous Technology, a Digital World and their Influence on People’s Feeling and Control of Presence in Everyday Life</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451831</span></li>
<li><span id="2021TeyssierEyecam">University), M. T. (S., University), M. K. (S., University), P. S. (S., University), B. F. (S., &amp; University), J. S. (S. (2021, May 7). <i>Eyecam: Revealing Relations Between Humans and Sensing Devices Through an Anthropomorphic Webcam</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/1122445.1122456</span></li>
<li><span id="2021MuthukumaranaCloth">of Auckland), S. M. (U., of Auckland), M. M. (U., of Applied Sciences Lübeck), D. M. (T. U., University), J. S. (S., of Auckland), P. S. (U., &amp; of Auckland), S. N. (U. (2021, May 7). <i>ClothTiles: Fabricating Customized Actuators on Textiles using 3D Printing and Shape-Memory Alloys</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445613</span></li>
<li><span id="2021KosmallaVirtual">Felix Kosmalla (DFKI, S. I. C., Campus), F. H. (S. I., Anke Hirsch (DFKI, S. I. C., Florian Daiber (DFKI, S. I. C., &amp; Antonio Krüger (DFKI, S. I. C. (2021, May 7). <i>VirtualLadder: Using Interactive Projections for Agility Ladder Training</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451638</span></li>
<li><span id="2021RhedenMind">van Rheden (University of Salzburg), V., of Salzburg), T. G. (U., of Salzburg), A. M. (U., University), R. P. (M., Pompidou), W. L. (I. R. C. A. M. C., Florian Daiber (DFKI, S. I. C., Elise van den Hoven (University of Technology Sydney, E. U. of T., &amp; University), F. F. M. (M. (2021, May 7). <i>Out of Your Mind!? Embodied Interaction in Sports</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3441329</span></li>
<li><span id="2021AlexandrovskyEvaluating">Dmitry Alexandrovsky (University of Bremen, D. M. L., Susanne Putze (University of Bremen, D. M. L., of Applied Sciences), V. S. (F. U., University), E. D. M. (A., University), J. D. S. (N., Denise Kahl (German Research Center for Artificial Intelligence (DFKI), S. I. C., Antonio Krüger (DFKI, S. I. C., &amp; Rainer Malaka (University of Bremen, D. M. L. (2021, May 7). <i>Evaluating User Experiences in Mixed Reality</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3441337</span></li>
<li><span id="Bentvelzen2021">University), M. B. (U., of Bremen), J. N. (U., of Technology), M. P. W. (L. U., &amp; University), P. W. W. (U. (2021, May 7). <i>The Development and Validation of the Technology-Supported Reflection Inventory</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445673</span></li>
<li><span id="Bentvelzen2021Barriers">University), M. B. (U., of Bremen), J. N. (U., &amp; University), P. W. W. (U. (2021, May 7). <i>The Technology-Mediated Reflection Model: Barriers and Assistance in Data-Driven Reflection</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445505</span></li>
<li><span id="Wozniak2021Running">University), P. W. W. (U., Zurich), M. Z. (E. T. H., GmbH), F. K. (B. E. T. E. S. O.- B. E., &amp; of Bremen), J. N. (U. (2021, May 7). <i>Making Sense of Complex Running Metrics Using a Modified Running Shoe</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445506</span></li>
<li><span id="Schmidt2021Beyond">München), A. S. (L. M. U., Munich), F. A. (B. U., &amp; Munich), V. M. (B. U. (2021, May 7). <i>Evaluation in Human-Computer Interaction – Beyond Lab Studies</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3445022</span></li>
<li><span id="Linxen2021Weird">of Basel), S. L. (U., of Applied Sciences), C. S. (H.-L. U., of Basel), F. B. (U., Lippstadt), V. C. (H. H.-, of Basel), K. O. (U., &amp; of Washington), K. R. (U. (2021, May 7). <i>How WEIRD is CHI?</i> https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445488</span></li>
<li><span id="Cannanure2021Across">University), V. K. C. (C. M., of Moratuwa), D. G. (U., of Applied Sciences), C. S. (H.-L. U., of Science, H. W.-T. (N. U., Technology), Bloomington), F. M. (I. U., of Washington), N. K. (U., (MIT), P. R.-C., &amp; Tech), N. K. (G. (2021, May 7). <i>Decolonizing HCI Across Borders</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3441348</span></li>
<li><span id="Koningsbruggen2021EmbodiedPW">van Koningsbruggen, R., Hengeveld, B., &amp; Alexander, J. (2021, May 7). Understanding the Design Space of Embodied Passwords Based on Muscle Memory. <i>Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445773</span></li>
<li><span id="2021MaFake">Munich), Y. M. (L. M. U., Munich), H. D. (L. M. U., &amp; Munich), A. B. (L. M. U. (2021, May 1). <i>Fake Moods: Can Users Trick an Emotion-Aware VoiceBot?</i> https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451744 </span></li>
<li><span id="2021KaltenhauserMEME">Annika Kaltenhauser (Ergosign GmbH &amp; LMU Munich), A. B. (L. M. U. M., Nađa Terzimehić (LMU Munich). (2021, May 1). <i>MEMEography: Understanding Users Through Internet Memes</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451581</span></li>
<li><span id="2021WozniakCreepy"><i>Creepy Technology: What Is It and How Do You Measure It?</i> (2021, May 1). https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445299</span></li>
<li><span id="2021VoelkelEliciting"><i>Eliciting and Analysing Users’ Envisioned Dialogues with Perfect Voice Assistants</i>. (2021, May 1). https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445536</span></li>
<li><span id="2021JascheComparison"><i>Comparison of Different Types of Augmented Reality Visualizations for Instructions</i>. (2021, May 1). https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445724</span></li>
<li><span id="FIT2021">Veronika Krauß (Fraunhofer FIT, U. S., Alexander Boden (Fraunhofer FIT, H. B.-R.-S., FIT), L. O. (F., &amp; FIT), R. R. (F. (2021, May 1). <i>Current Practices, Challenges, and Design Implications for Collaborative AR/VR Application Development</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445335</span></li>
<li><span id="2021WeberLook">Thomas Weber (LMU Munich), H. H. (L. M. U. M., Christina Winiker (LMU Munich). (2021, May 1). <i>A Closer Look at Machine Learning Code</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451679</span></li>
<li><span id="2021TerzimehicRealWorld">Munich), N. T. (L. M. U. (2021, May 1). <i>Real-World Presence in the Era of Ubiquitous Computing</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3443427</span></li>
<li><span id="Tachtler2021chiworkshop"><i>Artificially Intelligent Technology for the Margins: A Multidisciplinary Design Agenda</i>. (2021, May 1). https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3441333</span></li>
<li><span id="Dietz2021VRsneaky"><i>VRsneaky: Stepping into an Audible Virtual World with Gait-Aware Auditory Feedback</i>. (2021, May 1). https://doi.org/10.1145/3334480.3383168</span></li>
<li><span id="2021ReinhardtVisual">(PsyErgo), D. R., Group), J. B. (V. C., &amp; (PsyErgo), J. H. (2021, May 1). <i>Visual Interactive Privacy Policy: The Better Choice?</i> https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445465</span></li>
<li><span id="2021RixenExploring">University), J. O. R. (U., University), M. C. (U., University), Y. E. (U., University), E. R. (U., &amp; Paris), J. G. (T. (2021, May 1). <i>Exploring Augmented Visual Alterations in Interpersonal Communication</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445597</span></li>
<li><span id="2021LangnerMarvis">Dresden), R. L. (T. U., Dresden), M. S. (T. U., Dresden), W. B. (T. U., &amp; Dresden), R. D. (T. U. (2021, May 1). <i>MARVIS: Combining Mobile Devices and Augmented Reality for Visual Data Analysis</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445593</span></li>
<li><span id="2021StoeverInvestigating">of Darmstadt), A. S. (T. U., of Darmstadt), N. G. (T. U., of Darmstadt), S. K. (T. U., of Darmstadt), M. M. (T. U., &amp; Karola Marky (University of Glasgow, T. U. of D. (2021, May 1). <i>Investigating Simple Privacy Indicators for Supporting Users when Installing New Mobile Apps</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451791</span></li>
<li><span id="2021LiebersUnderstanding">of Duisburg-Essen), J. L. (U., in Cairo), M. A. (G. U., Munich), L. M. (B. U., of Duisburg-Essen), A. S. (U., of Duisburg-Essen), J. A. (U., of Duisburg-Essen), U. G. (U., Munich), F. A. (B. U., &amp; of Duisburg-Essen), S. S. (U. (2021, May 1). <i>Understanding User Identification in Virtual Reality Through Behavioral Biometrics and the Effect of Body Normalization</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445528</span></li>
<li><span id="2021HirzleCritical">University), T. H. (U., University), M. C. (U., University), E. R. (U., Paris), J. G. (T., &amp; of Stuttgart), A. B. (U. (2021, May 1). <i>A Critical Assessment of the Use of SSQ as a Measure of General Discomfort in VR Head-Mounted Displays</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445361</span></li>
<li><span id="2021KronesterPotential">Ingolstadt), M. K. (T. H., Ingolstadt), A. R. (T. H., &amp; Group), T. B. (B. M. W. (2021, May 1). <i>Potential of Wrist-worn Vibrotactile Feedback to Enhance the Perception of Virtual Objects during Mid-air Gestures</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451655</span></li>
<li><span id="2021SchussShare">Ingolstadt), M. S. (T. H., Ingolstadt), P. W. (T. H., &amp; ), A. R. (T. H. I. (2021, May 1). <i>Let’s Share a Ride into the Future: A Qalitative Study Comparing Hypothetical Implementation Scenarios of Automated Vehicles</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445609</span></li>
<li><span id="2021KaraosmanogluFeels">Hamburg), S. K. (U., of Waterloo), K. R. (U., University), D. W. (U., University), E. R. (U., Hamburg), F. S. (U., &amp; of Waterloo), L. E. N. (U. (2021, May 1). <i>Feels like Team Spirit: Biometric and Strategic Interdependence in Asymmetric Multiplayer VR Games</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445492</span></li>
<li><span id="2021HedeshyHummer">of Stuttgart), R. H. (U., of Stuttgart), C. K. (U., of Koblenz), R. M. (U., of Stuttgart, S. S. (U., &amp; of Southhampton), U. (2021, May 1). <i>Hummer: Text Entry by Gaze and Hum</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445501</span></li>
<li><span id="2021DangGesture">of Bayreuth), H. D. (U., &amp; of Bayreuth), D. B. (U. (2021, May 1). <i>GestureMap: Supporting Visual Analytics and Quantitative Analysis of Motion Elicitation Data by Learning 2D Embeddings</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445765</span></li>
<li><span id="2021YoungUngrounded">of Pennsylvania &amp; Max Planck Institute for Intelligent Systems), E. M. Y. (U., &amp; for Intelligent Systems), K. J. K. (M. P. I. (2021, May 1). <i>Ungrounded Vari-Dimensional Tactile Fingertip Feedback for Virtual Object Interaction</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445369</span></li>
<li><span id="2021MarkyFrets">of Darmstadt), K. M. (T. U., Schallkultur), A. W. (M. S., of Darmstadt), F. M. (T. U., of Darmstadt), M. S. (T. U., of Darmstadt), M. M. (T. U., &amp; of Darmstadt), T. K. (T. U. (2021, May 1). <i>Let’s Frets! Mastering Guitar Playing with Capacitive Sensing and Visual Guidance</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451536</span></li>
<li><span id="2021BuschekImpact">of Bayreuth), D. B. (U., Munich), M. Z. (L. M. U., &amp; Munich), M. E. (L. M. U. (2021, May 1). <i>The Impact of Multiple Parallel Phrase Suggestions on Email Input and Composition Behaviour of Native and Non-Native English Writers</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445372</span></li>
<li><span id="2021MarkyFretsPaper">of Darmstadt), K. M. (T. U., Schallkultur), A. W. (M. S., of Darmstadt), A. M. (T. U., of Darmstadt), F. B. (T. U., of Darmstadt), S. W. (T. U., of Darmstadt), M. S. (T. U., of Darmstadt), F. K. (T. U., of Darmstadt), F. M. (T. U., of Darmstadt), M. M. (T. U., &amp; of Darmstadt), T. K. (T. U. (2021, May 1). <i>Let’s Frets! Assisting Guitar Students during Practice via Capacitive Sensing</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445595</span></li>
<li><span id="2021FruchardSquish"><i>Squish This: Force Input on Soft Surfaces for Visual Targeting Tasks</i>. (2021, May 1). https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445623</span></li>
<li><span id="2021SharmaSoloFinger">Campus), A. S. (S. I., Campus), M. A. H. (S. I., Campus), D. B. (S. I., Campus), B. F. (S. I., of Copenhagen), J. M. I. (U., Campus), A. S. N. (S. I., Campus), D. K. (S. I., of Copenhagen), D. A. (U., &amp; Campus), J. S. (S. I. (2021, May 1). <i>SoloFinger: Robust Microgestures while Grasping Everyday Object</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445197</span></li>
<li><span id="2021PourjafarianBody">Campus), N. P. (S. I., Campus), M. K. (S. I., Campus), B. F. (S. I., Campus), S. M. (S. I., Dresden), K. K. (T. U., Campus), D. G. (S. I., Campus), P. S. (S. I., &amp; Campus), J. S. (S. I. (2021, May 1). <i>BodyStylus: Freehand On-Body Design and Fabrication of Epidermal Interfaces</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445475</span></li>
<li><span id="2021DietheiSharing">of Bremen), D. D. (U., of Bremen), J. N. (U., of Bremen), C. S. (U., of Bremen), E. S. (U., &amp; of Bremen), J. S. (U. (2021, May 1). <i>Sharing Heartbeats: Motivations of Citizen Scientists in Times of Crises</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445665</span></li>
<li><span id="2021MildnerEthical">of Bremen), T. M. (U., &amp; Interaction), G.-L. S. (H.-C. (2021, May 1). <i>Ethical User Interfaces: Exploring the Effects of Dark Patterns on Facebook</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451659</span></li>
<li><span id="2021DaiberEveryday">(DFKI), F. D., (DFKI), D. D., (DFKI), A. Z., of Bremen), T. D. (U., Hamburg), F. S. (U., Hamburg), O. J. A. N. (U., &amp; Leuven), A. L. S. (K. U. (2021, May 1). <i>Everyday Proxy Objects for Virtual Reality</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3441343</span></li>
<li><span id="2021ArboledaAssisting">Hochschule), S. A. A. (W., Hochschule), F. R. (W., Hochschule), T. D. (W., &amp; Hochschule), J. G. (W. (2021, May 1). <i>Assisting Manipulation and Grasping in Robot Teleoperation with Augmented Reality Visual Cues</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445398</span></li>
<li><span id="2021DreyQuestionnaires">University), T. D. (U., University), M. R. (U., &amp; University), E. R. (U. (2021, May 1). <i>Questionnaires and Qualitative Feedback Methods to Measure User Experience in Mixed Reality</i>. https://doi.org/-</span></li>
<li><span id="2021HubenschmidStream">of Konstanz), S. H. (U., of Konstanz), J. Z. (U., of Konstanz), S. B. (U., &amp; of Konstanz), H. R. (U. (2021, May 1). <i>STREAM: Exploring the Combination of Spatially-Aware Tablets with Augmented Reality Head-Mounted Displays for Immersive Analytics</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445298</span></li>
<li><span id="2021DuerrKitt">of Konstanz), M. D. (U., University), M. B. (A., of Konstanz), C. G. (U., of Konstanz), U. P. (U., of Konstanz), J. M. (U., &amp; of Konstanz), H. R. (U. (2021, May 1). <i>KiTT - The Kinaesthetics Transfer Teacher: Design and Evaluation of a Tablet-based System to Promote the Learning of Ergonomic Patient Transfers</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445496</span></li>
<li><span id="2021HollaenderTaxonomy">Munich), K. H. (L. M. U., Mark Colley (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., Enrico Rukzio (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., &amp; Munich), A. B. (L. M. U. (2021, May 1). <i>A Taxonomy of Vulnerable Road Users for HCI Based On A Systematic Literature Review</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445480</span></li>
<li><span id="2021SatkowskiInvestigating">Dresden), M. S. (T. U., &amp; Dresden), R. D. (T. U. (2021, May 1). <i>Investigating the Impact of Real-World Environments on the Perception of 2D Visualizations in Augmented Reality</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445330</span></li>
<li><span id="2021ColleyEffects">Mark Colley (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., Benjamin Eder (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., Jan Ole Rixen (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., &amp; Enrico Rukzio (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U. (2021, May 1). <i>Effects of Semantic Segmentation Visualization on Trust, Situation Awareness, and Cognitive Load in Highly Automated Vehicles</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445351</span></li>
<li><span id="2021JiangReverse">for Informatics), Y. J. (M. P. I., University), W. S. (S. F., &amp; of Bath), C. L. (U. (2021, May 1). <i>ReverseORC: Reverse Engineering of Resizable User Interface Layouts with OR-Constraints</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445043</span></li>
<li><span id="2021SchmitzSnap">of Darmstadt), M. S. (T. U., of Darmstadt), J. R. (T. U., of Darmstadt), F. M. (T. U., of Darmstadt), S. K. (T. U., &amp; of Darmstadt), M. M. (T. U. (2021, May 1). <i>Oh, Snap! A Fabrication Pipeline to Magnetically Connect Conventional and 3D-Printed Electronics</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445641</span></li>
<li><span id="2021SchmitzItsy">of Darmstadt), M. S. (T. U., of Darmstadt), F. M. (T. U., of Darmstadt), M. M. (T. U., of Darmstadt), J. R. (T. U., &amp; of Stuttgart), H. V. L. (U. (2021, May 1). <i>Itsy-Bits: Fabrication and Recognition of 3D-Printed Tangibles with Small Footprints on Capacitive Touchscreens</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445502</span></li>
<li><span id="2021SavinoCycling">of Bremen), G.-L. S. (U., von Sawitzky (Technische Hochschule Ingolstadt), T., of Darmstadt), A. M. (T. U., University), M. S. (L., University), P. W. W. (U., University), M. L. (A., of New Hampshire), A. L. K. (U., Ingolstadt), A. R. (T. H., &amp; of Lapland), J. H. (U. (2021). <i>Cycling@CHI: Towards a Research Agenda for HCI in the Bike Lane</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3441316</span></li>
<li><span id="2021KilianEMPiano">Munich), A. K. (L. M. U., Munich), J. K. (L. M. U., Darmstadt), T. K. (T. U., Munich), A. S. (L. M. U., &amp; University), P. W. W. (U. (2021, May 1). <i>EMPiano: Electromyographic Pitch Control on the Piano Keyboard</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451556</span></li>
<li><span id="2021HaliburtonQuick">Munich), L. H. (L. M. U., Munich), M. H. (L. M. U., Munich), A. S. (L. M. U., &amp; Darmstadt), T. K. (T. U. (2021, May 1). <i>Quick, Print This Page! The Value of Analogue Media in a Digital World</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3450375</span></li>
<li><span id="2021MatviienkoQuantified">of Darmstadt), A. M. (T. U., University), F. H. (H., &amp; of Technology), B. P. (E. U. (2021, May 1). <i>Quantified Cycling Safety: Towards a Mobile Sensing Platform to Understand Perceived Safety of Cyclists</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451678</span></li>
<li><span id="2021MatviienkoVRtangibles">of Darmstadt), A. M. (T. U., of Darmstadt), M. L. (T. U., of Darmstadt), F. M. (T. U., of Darmstadt), M. S. (T. U., &amp; of Darmstadt), M. M. (T. U. (2021, May 1). <i>VRtangibles: Assisting Children in Creating Virtual Scenes using Tangible Objects and Touch Input</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451671</span></li>
<li><span id="2021DelgadoActPad">Sarah Delgado Rodriguez (Bundeswehr University Munich, L. M. U. M., Sarah Prange (Bundeswehr University Munich, L. M. U. M., Lukas Mecke (Bundeswehr University Munich, L. M. U. M., &amp; Munich), F. A. (B. U. (2021, May 1). <i>ActPad – A Smart Desk Platform to Enable User Interaction with IoT Devices</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451825</span></li>
<li><span id="2021AlexandrovskySerious">Dmitry Alexandrovsky (DMLab, U. of B., Dublin), M. A. F. (U. C., of Bremen), J. G. (U., Susanne Putze (DMLab, U. of B., of Technology), M. V. B. (E. U., Rainer Malaka (DMLab, U. of B., &amp; of Saskatchewan), R. L. M. (U. (2021, May 1). <i>Serious Snacking: A Survival Analysis of how Snacking Mechanics Affect Attrition in a Mobile Serious Game</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445689</span></li>
<li><span id="2021deCastroOn">de Castro Leal (University of Siegen), D., University), A. S. (N., &amp; of Siegen), M. K. (U. (2021, May 1). <i>On Activism and Academia: Reflecting Together and Sharing Experiences Among Critical Friends</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445263</span></li>
<li><span id="2021AbdrabouThink">Munich), Y. A. (B. U., Munich), Y. A. (B. U., of Glasgow), M. K. (U., &amp; Munich), F. A. (B. U. (2021, May 1). <i>Think Harder! Investigating the Effect of Password Strength on Cognitive Load during Password Creation </i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451636</span></li>
<li><span id="2021MakelaHidden">Munich), V. M. (L. M. U., Munich), J. K. (L. M. U., College), M. H. (W., Munich), F. A. (B. U., &amp; Munich), A. S. (L. M. U. (2021, May 1). <i>Hidden Interaction Techniques: Concealed Information Acquisition and Texting on Smartphones and Wearables</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445504</span></li>
<li><span id="2021PrangePriView">Sarah Prange (Bundeswehr University Munich, L. M. U. M., in Cairo), A. S. (G. U., Munich), R. P. (L. M. U., Munich), Y. A. (B. U., &amp; Munich), F. A. (B. U. (2021, May 1). <i>PriView - Exploring Visualisations to Support Users’ Privacy Awareness</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445067</span></li>
<li><span id="2021BueschelMiria">Wolfgang Büschel (Interactive Media Lab Dresden, T. U. D., Anke Lehmann (Interactive Media Lab Dresden, T. U. D., &amp; Raimund Dachselt (Interactive Media Lab Dresden, T. U. D. (2021, May 1). <i>MIRIA: A Mixed Reality Toolkit for the In-Situ Visualization and Analysis of Spatio-Temporal Interaction Data</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445651</span></li>
<li><span id="2021AbdullahFast">Institute), M. A. (H. P., Institute), M. T. (H. P., Institute), Y. K. (H. P., Institute), S. K. (H. P., Institute), R. K. (H. P., Institute), J. S. (H. P., Institute), T. R. (H. P., &amp; Institute), P. B. (H. P. (2021, May 1). <i>Fastforce: Real-Time Reinforcement of Laser-Cut Structures</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445466</span></li>
<li><span id="2021RoumenAssembler">Institute), T. R. (H. P., Institute), Y. K. (H. P., Institute), I. A. (H. P., Institute), C. L. (H. P., Institute), M. B. (H. P., Institute), E. B. (H. P., Institute), L. S. (H. P., Institute), L. R. (H. P., Institute), C. G. (H. P., Institute), P. C. (H. P., Institute), B. H. (H. P., Institute), M. A. (H. P., &amp; Institute), P. B. (H. P. (2021, May 1). <i>assembler3: 3D Reconstruction of Laser-Cut Models</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445453</span></li>
<li><span id="2021OsmersRole">Clausthal), N. O. (T. U., Clausthal), M. P. (T. U., Clausthal), O. B. (T. U., Clausthal), G. B. (T. U., Clausthal), M. J. (T. U., &amp; Clausthal), N. K. (T. U. (2021, May 1). <i>The Role of Social Presence for Cooperation in Augmented Reality on Head Mounted Devices</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445633</span></li>
<li><span id="2021ReinschluesselStudy">Bremen), A. V. R. (U., Bremen), T. M. (U., Bremen), T. D. (U., für Viszeralchirurgie), V. U. (U., (cirp GmbH), T. L., für Viszeralchirurgie), D. W. (U., for Digital Medicine MEVIS), A. S. (F. I., &amp; Bremen), R. M. (U. (2021, May 1). <i>A Study on the Size of Tangible Organ-Shaped Controllers for Exploring Medical Data in VR</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451594</span></li>
<li><span id="2021BenjaminMachine">(UTwente), J. J. B., Anhalt), A. B. (H. S., Berkeley), N. M. (U. C., &amp; of Washington), J. P. (U. (2021, May 1). <i>Machine Learning Uncertainty as a Design Material: A Post-Phenomenological Inquiry into Pragmatic Concepts for Design Research</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445481</span></li>
<li><span id="2021YooUnderstanding">Surrey), M. Y. Y. (S. F. U., Surrey), W. O. (S. F. U., &amp; Anhalt), A. B. (H. S. (2021, May 1). <i>Understanding Everyday Experiences of Reminiscence for People Living with Blindness: Practices, Tensions and Probing New Design Possibilities.</i> https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445212</span></li>
<li><span id="2021RzayevReading">of Regensburg), R. R. (U., of Regensburg), P. U. (U., of Regensburg), S. G. (U., of Applied Sciences), V. S. (F. U., &amp; of Regensburg), N. H. (U. (2021, May 1). <i>Reading in VR: The Effect of Text Presentation Type and Location</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445606</span></li>
<li><span id="2021KocurPhysiological">of Regensburg), M. K. (U., of Regensburg), F. H. (U., of Applied Sciences), V. S. (F. U., University), P. W. W. (U., of Regensburg), C. W. (U., &amp; of Regensburg), N. H. (U. (2021, May 1). <i>Physiological and Perceptual Responses to Athletic Avatars while Cycling in Virtual Reality</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445160</span></li>
<li><span id="2021LeShortcut">of Stuttgart), H. V. L. (U., Munich), S. M. (L. M. U., of Stuttgart), M. W. (U., of Stuttgart), J. V. (U., of Stuttgart), H. W. (U., &amp; of Regensburg), N. H. (U. (2021). <i>Shortcut Gestures for Mobile Text Editing on Fully Touch Sensitive Smartphones</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3396233</span></li>
<li><span id="2021EnsGrand">University), B. E. (M., of Edinburgh), B. B. (U., University), M. C. (M., Data61), U. E. (C. S. I. R. O., of Toulouse), M. S. (I. R. I. T.- U., of Calgary), W. W. (U., University), A. P. (I. + M., Christoph Anthes (HIVE, U. of A. S. U. A., Dresden), W. B. (T. U., Khoury), C. D. (N. U., University), T. D. (M., of Applied Sciences, J. G. (C. U., Arts), Jason H. Haga (Digital Architecture Promotion Center, N. I. of A. I. S., Technology), Nurit Kirshenbaum (LAVA, U. of H. at M., Dylan Kobayashi (LAVA, U. of H. at M., University), T. L. (H., University), M. O. (T., … University), Y. Y. (H. (2021, May 1). <i>Grand Challenges in Immersive Analytics</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3446866</span></li>
<li><span id="Clarke2021Fires">Clarke, L., Hornecker, E., &amp; Ruthven, I. (2021, January 1). Fighting Fires and Powering Steam Locomotives: Distribution of Control and Its Role in Social Interaction at Tangible Interactive Museum Exhibits. <i>Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</i>. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445534</span></li></ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Martin Feick (DFKI, S. I. C., Niko Kleer (DFKI, S. I. C., André Zenner (Saarland University &amp; DFKI, S. I. C., of Toronto), A. T. (U., &amp; Antonio Krüger (DFKI, S. I. C. (2021, May 8). Visuo-haptic Illusions for Linear Translation and Stretching using Physical Proxies in Virtual Reality. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445456 DFKI), A. Z. (S. U. &amp;, DFKI), H. M. K. (S. U. &amp;, &amp; DFKI), A. K. (S. U. &amp;. (2021, May 8). HaRT - The Virtual Reality Hand Redirection Toolkit. https://doi.org/0.1145/3411763.3451814 Philip Weber (Cyber-Physical Systems, U. of S., Thomas Ludwig (Cyber-Physical Systems, U. of S., Sabrina Brodesser (Cyber-Physical Systems, U. of S., &amp; Laura Grönewald (Cyber-Physical Systems, U. of S. (2021, May 8). “It’s a kind of art!”: Understanding Food Influencers as Influential Content Creators. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445607 Weizhou Luo (Interactive Media Lab Dresden, T. U. D., Anke Lehmann (Interactive Media Lab Dresden, T. U. D., Yushan Yang (Interactive Media Lab Dresden, T. U. D., &amp; Raimund Dachselt (Interactive Media Lab Dresden, T. U. D. (2021, May 7). Investigating Document Layout and Placement Strategies for Collaborative Sensemaking in Augmented Reality. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451588 Siegen), M. K. (U., Siegen), A. W. (U., de Castro Leal (Universität Siegen), D., Siegen), D. R. (U., &amp; Siegen), V. W. (U. (2021, May 7). It Takes More Than One Hand to Clap: On the Role of ‘Care’ in Maintaining Design Results. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445389 of Siegen), M. M. (U., of Siegen), S. R. (U., of Siegen), K. A. (U., University), N. B.-R. (R., Shaimaa Lazem (City of Scientifc Research, T. A., of Science, A. P. (N. U., Technology), S. H. (U. of C., University), V. V. (N., of Sussex), A. L. (U., of Siegen), D. R. (U., &amp; of Siegen), V. W. (U. (2021, May 7). Coping with Messiness in Ethnography: Authority, Bias and Immersion in ethnographic Fieldwork in the non-Western World. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3441328 Designing for New Forms of Vulnerability: Exploring transformation and empowerment in times of COVID-19. (2021, May 7). https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3441339 Munich), C. S. (L. M. U., Munich), D. I. (L. M. U., Munich), F. B. (L. M. U., &amp; of Bayreuth), D. B. (U. (2021, May 7). LYLO – Exploring Disclosed Configurations for Inter-Personal Location Sharing. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451652 University), K. S. (R. W. T. H. A., University), J. M. (R. W. T. H. A., University), J. B. (R. W. T. H. A., &amp; and Jim Hollan (University of California, S. D. (2021, May 7). From Detectables to Inspectables: Understanding Qualitative Analysis of Audiovisual Data. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445458​ Leon Müller (LMU Munich, G., Munich), K. P. (B. U., Institut, J. G. (T. P.- L. T. C. I., Polytechnique de Paris, F., Paris, Bastian Pfleging (Eindhoven University of Technology, N., Eindhoven, LMU Munich, G., Munich, Sarah Prange (Bundeswehr University Munich, G., Munich, LMU Munich, G., Munich, &amp; Florian Alt (Bundeswehr University Munich, G., Munich. (2021, May 7). SpatialProto: Exploring Real-World Motion Captures for Rapid Prototyping of Interactive Mixed Reality. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445560 Munich), N. T. (L. M. U., Munich), C. G. (L. M. U., of Freiburg), R. H. (U., &amp; Munich), H. H. (L. M. U. (2021, May 7). On Ubiquitous Technology, a Digital World and their Influence on People’s Feeling and Control of Presence in Everyday Life. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451831 University), M. T. (S., University), M. K. (S., University), P. S. (S., University), B. F. (S., &amp; University), J. S. (S. (2021, May 7). Eyecam: Revealing Relations Between Humans and Sensing Devices Through an Anthropomorphic Webcam. https://doi.org/10.1145/1122445.1122456 of Auckland), S. M. (U., of Auckland), M. M. (U., of Applied Sciences Lübeck), D. M. (T. U., University), J. S. (S., of Auckland), P. S. (U., &amp; of Auckland), S. N. (U. (2021, May 7). ClothTiles: Fabricating Customized Actuators on Textiles using 3D Printing and Shape-Memory Alloys. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445613 Felix Kosmalla (DFKI, S. I. C., Campus), F. H. (S. I., Anke Hirsch (DFKI, S. I. C., Florian Daiber (DFKI, S. I. C., &amp; Antonio Krüger (DFKI, S. I. C. (2021, May 7). VirtualLadder: Using Interactive Projections for Agility Ladder Training. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451638 van Rheden (University of Salzburg), V., of Salzburg), T. G. (U., of Salzburg), A. M. (U., University), R. P. (M., Pompidou), W. L. (I. R. C. A. M. C., Florian Daiber (DFKI, S. I. C., Elise van den Hoven (University of Technology Sydney, E. U. of T., &amp; University), F. F. M. (M. (2021, May 7). Out of Your Mind!? Embodied Interaction in Sports. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3441329 Dmitry Alexandrovsky (University of Bremen, D. M. L., Susanne Putze (University of Bremen, D. M. L., of Applied Sciences), V. S. (F. U., University), E. D. M. (A., University), J. D. S. (N., Denise Kahl (German Research Center for Artificial Intelligence (DFKI), S. I. C., Antonio Krüger (DFKI, S. I. C., &amp; Rainer Malaka (University of Bremen, D. M. L. (2021, May 7). Evaluating User Experiences in Mixed Reality. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3441337 University), M. B. (U., of Bremen), J. N. (U., of Technology), M. P. W. (L. U., &amp; University), P. W. W. (U. (2021, May 7). The Development and Validation of the Technology-Supported Reflection Inventory. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445673 University), M. B. (U., of Bremen), J. N. (U., &amp; University), P. W. W. (U. (2021, May 7). The Technology-Mediated Reflection Model: Barriers and Assistance in Data-Driven Reflection. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445505 University), P. W. W. (U., Zurich), M. Z. (E. T. H., GmbH), F. K. (B. E. T. E. S. O.- B. E., &amp; of Bremen), J. N. (U. (2021, May 7). Making Sense of Complex Running Metrics Using a Modified Running Shoe. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445506 München), A. S. (L. M. U., Munich), F. A. (B. U., &amp; Munich), V. M. (B. U. (2021, May 7). Evaluation in Human-Computer Interaction – Beyond Lab Studies. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3445022 of Basel), S. L. (U., of Applied Sciences), C. S. (H.-L. U., of Basel), F. B. (U., Lippstadt), V. C. (H. H.-, of Basel), K. O. (U., &amp; of Washington), K. R. (U. (2021, May 7). How WEIRD is CHI? https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445488 University), V. K. C. (C. M., of Moratuwa), D. G. (U., of Applied Sciences), C. S. (H.-L. U., of Science, H. W.-T. (N. U., Technology), Bloomington), F. M. (I. U., of Washington), N. K. (U., (MIT), P. R.-C., &amp; Tech), N. K. (G. (2021, May 7). Decolonizing HCI Across Borders. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3441348 van Koningsbruggen, R., Hengeveld, B., &amp; Alexander, J. (2021, May 7). Understanding the Design Space of Embodied Passwords Based on Muscle Memory. Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445773 Munich), Y. M. (L. M. U., Munich), H. D. (L. M. U., &amp; Munich), A. B. (L. M. U. (2021, May 1). Fake Moods: Can Users Trick an Emotion-Aware VoiceBot? https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451744 Annika Kaltenhauser (Ergosign GmbH &amp; LMU Munich), A. B. (L. M. U. M., Nađa Terzimehić (LMU Munich). (2021, May 1). MEMEography: Understanding Users Through Internet Memes. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451581 Creepy Technology: What Is It and How Do You Measure It? (2021, May 1). https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445299 Eliciting and Analysing Users’ Envisioned Dialogues with Perfect Voice Assistants. (2021, May 1). https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445536 Comparison of Different Types of Augmented Reality Visualizations for Instructions. (2021, May 1). https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445724 Veronika Krauß (Fraunhofer FIT, U. S., Alexander Boden (Fraunhofer FIT, H. B.-R.-S., FIT), L. O. (F., &amp; FIT), R. R. (F. (2021, May 1). Current Practices, Challenges, and Design Implications for Collaborative AR/VR Application Development. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445335 Thomas Weber (LMU Munich), H. H. (L. M. U. M., Christina Winiker (LMU Munich). (2021, May 1). A Closer Look at Machine Learning Code. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451679 Munich), N. T. (L. M. U. (2021, May 1). Real-World Presence in the Era of Ubiquitous Computing. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3443427 Artificially Intelligent Technology for the Margins: A Multidisciplinary Design Agenda. (2021, May 1). https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3441333 VRsneaky: Stepping into an Audible Virtual World with Gait-Aware Auditory Feedback. (2021, May 1). https://doi.org/10.1145/3334480.3383168 (PsyErgo), D. R., Group), J. B. (V. C., &amp; (PsyErgo), J. H. (2021, May 1). Visual Interactive Privacy Policy: The Better Choice? https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445465 University), J. O. R. (U., University), M. C. (U., University), Y. E. (U., University), E. R. (U., &amp; Paris), J. G. (T. (2021, May 1). Exploring Augmented Visual Alterations in Interpersonal Communication. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445597 Dresden), R. L. (T. U., Dresden), M. S. (T. U., Dresden), W. B. (T. U., &amp; Dresden), R. D. (T. U. (2021, May 1). MARVIS: Combining Mobile Devices and Augmented Reality for Visual Data Analysis. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445593 of Darmstadt), A. S. (T. U., of Darmstadt), N. G. (T. U., of Darmstadt), S. K. (T. U., of Darmstadt), M. M. (T. U., &amp; Karola Marky (University of Glasgow, T. U. of D. (2021, May 1). Investigating Simple Privacy Indicators for Supporting Users when Installing New Mobile Apps. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451791 of Duisburg-Essen), J. L. (U., in Cairo), M. A. (G. U., Munich), L. M. (B. U., of Duisburg-Essen), A. S. (U., of Duisburg-Essen), J. A. (U., of Duisburg-Essen), U. G. (U., Munich), F. A. (B. U., &amp; of Duisburg-Essen), S. S. (U. (2021, May 1). Understanding User Identification in Virtual Reality Through Behavioral Biometrics and the Effect of Body Normalization. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445528 University), T. H. (U., University), M. C. (U., University), E. R. (U., Paris), J. G. (T., &amp; of Stuttgart), A. B. (U. (2021, May 1). A Critical Assessment of the Use of SSQ as a Measure of General Discomfort in VR Head-Mounted Displays. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445361 Ingolstadt), M. K. (T. H., Ingolstadt), A. R. (T. H., &amp; Group), T. B. (B. M. W. (2021, May 1). Potential of Wrist-worn Vibrotactile Feedback to Enhance the Perception of Virtual Objects during Mid-air Gestures. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451655 Ingolstadt), M. S. (T. H., Ingolstadt), P. W. (T. H., &amp; ), A. R. (T. H. I. (2021, May 1). Let’s Share a Ride into the Future: A Qalitative Study Comparing Hypothetical Implementation Scenarios of Automated Vehicles. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445609 Hamburg), S. K. (U., of Waterloo), K. R. (U., University), D. W. (U., University), E. R. (U., Hamburg), F. S. (U., &amp; of Waterloo), L. E. N. (U. (2021, May 1). Feels like Team Spirit: Biometric and Strategic Interdependence in Asymmetric Multiplayer VR Games. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445492 of Stuttgart), R. H. (U., of Stuttgart), C. K. (U., of Koblenz), R. M. (U., of Stuttgart, S. S. (U., &amp; of Southhampton), U. (2021, May 1). Hummer: Text Entry by Gaze and Hum. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445501 of Bayreuth), H. D. (U., &amp; of Bayreuth), D. B. (U. (2021, May 1). GestureMap: Supporting Visual Analytics and Quantitative Analysis of Motion Elicitation Data by Learning 2D Embeddings. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445765 of Pennsylvania &amp; Max Planck Institute for Intelligent Systems), E. M. Y. (U., &amp; for Intelligent Systems), K. J. K. (M. P. I. (2021, May 1). Ungrounded Vari-Dimensional Tactile Fingertip Feedback for Virtual Object Interaction. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445369 of Darmstadt), K. M. (T. U., Schallkultur), A. W. (M. S., of Darmstadt), F. M. (T. U., of Darmstadt), M. S. (T. U., of Darmstadt), M. M. (T. U., &amp; of Darmstadt), T. K. (T. U. (2021, May 1). Let’s Frets! Mastering Guitar Playing with Capacitive Sensing and Visual Guidance. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451536 of Bayreuth), D. B. (U., Munich), M. Z. (L. M. U., &amp; Munich), M. E. (L. M. U. (2021, May 1). The Impact of Multiple Parallel Phrase Suggestions on Email Input and Composition Behaviour of Native and Non-Native English Writers. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445372 of Darmstadt), K. M. (T. U., Schallkultur), A. W. (M. S., of Darmstadt), A. M. (T. U., of Darmstadt), F. B. (T. U., of Darmstadt), S. W. (T. U., of Darmstadt), M. S. (T. U., of Darmstadt), F. K. (T. U., of Darmstadt), F. M. (T. U., of Darmstadt), M. M. (T. U., &amp; of Darmstadt), T. K. (T. U. (2021, May 1). Let’s Frets! Assisting Guitar Students during Practice via Capacitive Sensing. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445595 Squish This: Force Input on Soft Surfaces for Visual Targeting Tasks. (2021, May 1). https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445623 Campus), A. S. (S. I., Campus), M. A. H. (S. I., Campus), D. B. (S. I., Campus), B. F. (S. I., of Copenhagen), J. M. I. (U., Campus), A. S. N. (S. I., Campus), D. K. (S. I., of Copenhagen), D. A. (U., &amp; Campus), J. S. (S. I. (2021, May 1). SoloFinger: Robust Microgestures while Grasping Everyday Object. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445197 Campus), N. P. (S. I., Campus), M. K. (S. I., Campus), B. F. (S. I., Campus), S. M. (S. I., Dresden), K. K. (T. U., Campus), D. G. (S. I., Campus), P. S. (S. I., &amp; Campus), J. S. (S. I. (2021, May 1). BodyStylus: Freehand On-Body Design and Fabrication of Epidermal Interfaces. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445475 of Bremen), D. D. (U., of Bremen), J. N. (U., of Bremen), C. S. (U., of Bremen), E. S. (U., &amp; of Bremen), J. S. (U. (2021, May 1). Sharing Heartbeats: Motivations of Citizen Scientists in Times of Crises. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445665 of Bremen), T. M. (U., &amp; Interaction), G.-L. S. (H.-C. (2021, May 1). Ethical User Interfaces: Exploring the Effects of Dark Patterns on Facebook. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451659 (DFKI), F. D., (DFKI), D. D., (DFKI), A. Z., of Bremen), T. D. (U., Hamburg), F. S. (U., Hamburg), O. J. A. N. (U., &amp; Leuven), A. L. S. (K. U. (2021, May 1). Everyday Proxy Objects for Virtual Reality. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3441343 Hochschule), S. A. A. (W., Hochschule), F. R. (W., Hochschule), T. D. (W., &amp; Hochschule), J. G. (W. (2021, May 1). Assisting Manipulation and Grasping in Robot Teleoperation with Augmented Reality Visual Cues. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445398 University), T. D. (U., University), M. R. (U., &amp; University), E. R. (U. (2021, May 1). Questionnaires and Qualitative Feedback Methods to Measure User Experience in Mixed Reality. https://doi.org/- of Konstanz), S. H. (U., of Konstanz), J. Z. (U., of Konstanz), S. B. (U., &amp; of Konstanz), H. R. (U. (2021, May 1). STREAM: Exploring the Combination of Spatially-Aware Tablets with Augmented Reality Head-Mounted Displays for Immersive Analytics. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445298 of Konstanz), M. D. (U., University), M. B. (A., of Konstanz), C. G. (U., of Konstanz), U. P. (U., of Konstanz), J. M. (U., &amp; of Konstanz), H. R. (U. (2021, May 1). KiTT - The Kinaesthetics Transfer Teacher: Design and Evaluation of a Tablet-based System to Promote the Learning of Ergonomic Patient Transfers. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445496 Munich), K. H. (L. M. U., Mark Colley (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., Enrico Rukzio (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., &amp; Munich), A. B. (L. M. U. (2021, May 1). A Taxonomy of Vulnerable Road Users for HCI Based On A Systematic Literature Review. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445480 Dresden), M. S. (T. U., &amp; Dresden), R. D. (T. U. (2021, May 1). Investigating the Impact of Real-World Environments on the Perception of 2D Visualizations in Augmented Reality. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445330 Mark Colley (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., Benjamin Eder (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., Jan Ole Rixen (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U., &amp; Enrico Rukzio (Institute of Media Informatics, U. U. (2021, May 1). Effects of Semantic Segmentation Visualization on Trust, Situation Awareness, and Cognitive Load in Highly Automated Vehicles. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445351 for Informatics), Y. J. (M. P. I., University), W. S. (S. F., &amp; of Bath), C. L. (U. (2021, May 1). ReverseORC: Reverse Engineering of Resizable User Interface Layouts with OR-Constraints. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445043 of Darmstadt), M. S. (T. U., of Darmstadt), J. R. (T. U., of Darmstadt), F. M. (T. U., of Darmstadt), S. K. (T. U., &amp; of Darmstadt), M. M. (T. U. (2021, May 1). Oh, Snap! A Fabrication Pipeline to Magnetically Connect Conventional and 3D-Printed Electronics. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445641 of Darmstadt), M. S. (T. U., of Darmstadt), F. M. (T. U., of Darmstadt), M. M. (T. U., of Darmstadt), J. R. (T. U., &amp; of Stuttgart), H. V. L. (U. (2021, May 1). Itsy-Bits: Fabrication and Recognition of 3D-Printed Tangibles with Small Footprints on Capacitive Touchscreens. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445502 of Bremen), G.-L. S. (U., von Sawitzky (Technische Hochschule Ingolstadt), T., of Darmstadt), A. M. (T. U., University), M. S. (L., University), P. W. W. (U., University), M. L. (A., of New Hampshire), A. L. K. (U., Ingolstadt), A. R. (T. H., &amp; of Lapland), J. H. (U. (2021). Cycling@CHI: Towards a Research Agenda for HCI in the Bike Lane. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3441316 Munich), A. K. (L. M. U., Munich), J. K. (L. M. U., Darmstadt), T. K. (T. U., Munich), A. S. (L. M. U., &amp; University), P. W. W. (U. (2021, May 1). EMPiano: Electromyographic Pitch Control on the Piano Keyboard. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451556 Munich), L. H. (L. M. U., Munich), M. H. (L. M. U., Munich), A. S. (L. M. U., &amp; Darmstadt), T. K. (T. U. (2021, May 1). Quick, Print This Page! The Value of Analogue Media in a Digital World. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3450375 of Darmstadt), A. M. (T. U., University), F. H. (H., &amp; of Technology), B. P. (E. U. (2021, May 1). Quantified Cycling Safety: Towards a Mobile Sensing Platform to Understand Perceived Safety of Cyclists. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451678 of Darmstadt), A. M. (T. U., of Darmstadt), M. L. (T. U., of Darmstadt), F. M. (T. U., of Darmstadt), M. S. (T. U., &amp; of Darmstadt), M. M. (T. U. (2021, May 1). VRtangibles: Assisting Children in Creating Virtual Scenes using Tangible Objects and Touch Input. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451671 Sarah Delgado Rodriguez (Bundeswehr University Munich, L. M. U. M., Sarah Prange (Bundeswehr University Munich, L. M. U. M., Lukas Mecke (Bundeswehr University Munich, L. M. U. M., &amp; Munich), F. A. (B. U. (2021, May 1). ActPad – A Smart Desk Platform to Enable User Interaction with IoT Devices. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451825 Dmitry Alexandrovsky (DMLab, U. of B., Dublin), M. A. F. (U. C., of Bremen), J. G. (U., Susanne Putze (DMLab, U. of B., of Technology), M. V. B. (E. U., Rainer Malaka (DMLab, U. of B., &amp; of Saskatchewan), R. L. M. (U. (2021, May 1). Serious Snacking: A Survival Analysis of how Snacking Mechanics Affect Attrition in a Mobile Serious Game. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445689 de Castro Leal (University of Siegen), D., University), A. S. (N., &amp; of Siegen), M. K. (U. (2021, May 1). On Activism and Academia: Reflecting Together and Sharing Experiences Among Critical Friends. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445263 Munich), Y. A. (B. U., Munich), Y. A. (B. U., of Glasgow), M. K. (U., &amp; Munich), F. A. (B. U. (2021, May 1). Think Harder! Investigating the Effect of Password Strength on Cognitive Load during Password Creation . https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451636 Munich), V. M. (L. M. U., Munich), J. K. (L. M. U., College), M. H. (W., Munich), F. A. (B. U., &amp; Munich), A. S. (L. M. U. (2021, May 1). Hidden Interaction Techniques: Concealed Information Acquisition and Texting on Smartphones and Wearables. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445504 Sarah Prange (Bundeswehr University Munich, L. M. U. M., in Cairo), A. S. (G. U., Munich), R. P. (L. M. U., Munich), Y. A. (B. U., &amp; Munich), F. A. (B. U. (2021, May 1). PriView - Exploring Visualisations to Support Users’ Privacy Awareness. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445067 Wolfgang Büschel (Interactive Media Lab Dresden, T. U. D., Anke Lehmann (Interactive Media Lab Dresden, T. U. D., &amp; Raimund Dachselt (Interactive Media Lab Dresden, T. U. D. (2021, May 1). MIRIA: A Mixed Reality Toolkit for the In-Situ Visualization and Analysis of Spatio-Temporal Interaction Data. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445651 Institute), M. A. (H. P., Institute), M. T. (H. P., Institute), Y. K. (H. P., Institute), S. K. (H. P., Institute), R. K. (H. P., Institute), J. S. (H. P., Institute), T. R. (H. P., &amp; Institute), P. B. (H. P. (2021, May 1). Fastforce: Real-Time Reinforcement of Laser-Cut Structures. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445466 Institute), T. R. (H. P., Institute), Y. K. (H. P., Institute), I. A. (H. P., Institute), C. L. (H. P., Institute), M. B. (H. P., Institute), E. B. (H. P., Institute), L. S. (H. P., Institute), L. R. (H. P., Institute), C. G. (H. P., Institute), P. C. (H. P., Institute), B. H. (H. P., Institute), M. A. (H. P., &amp; Institute), P. B. (H. P. (2021, May 1). assembler3: 3D Reconstruction of Laser-Cut Models. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445453 Clausthal), N. O. (T. U., Clausthal), M. P. (T. U., Clausthal), O. B. (T. U., Clausthal), G. B. (T. U., Clausthal), M. J. (T. U., &amp; Clausthal), N. K. (T. U. (2021, May 1). The Role of Social Presence for Cooperation in Augmented Reality on Head Mounted Devices. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445633 Bremen), A. V. R. (U., Bremen), T. M. (U., Bremen), T. D. (U., für Viszeralchirurgie), V. U. (U., (cirp GmbH), T. L., für Viszeralchirurgie), D. W. (U., for Digital Medicine MEVIS), A. S. (F. I., &amp; Bremen), R. M. (U. (2021, May 1). A Study on the Size of Tangible Organ-Shaped Controllers for Exploring Medical Data in VR. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411763.3451594 (UTwente), J. J. B., Anhalt), A. B. (H. S., Berkeley), N. M. (U. C., &amp; of Washington), J. P. (U. (2021, May 1). Machine Learning Uncertainty as a Design Material: A Post-Phenomenological Inquiry into Pragmatic Concepts for Design Research. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445481 Surrey), M. Y. Y. (S. F. U., Surrey), W. O. (S. F. U., &amp; Anhalt), A. B. (H. S. (2021, May 1). Understanding Everyday Experiences of Reminiscence for People Living with Blindness: Practices, Tensions and Probing New Design Possibilities. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445212 of Regensburg), R. R. (U., of Regensburg), P. U. (U., of Regensburg), S. G. (U., of Applied Sciences), V. S. (F. U., &amp; of Regensburg), N. H. (U. (2021, May 1). Reading in VR: The Effect of Text Presentation Type and Location. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445606 of Regensburg), M. K. (U., of Regensburg), F. H. (U., of Applied Sciences), V. S. (F. U., University), P. W. W. (U., of Regensburg), C. W. (U., &amp; of Regensburg), N. H. (U. (2021, May 1). Physiological and Perceptual Responses to Athletic Avatars while Cycling in Virtual Reality. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445160 of Stuttgart), H. V. L. (U., Munich), S. M. (L. M. U., of Stuttgart), M. W. (U., of Stuttgart), J. V. (U., of Stuttgart), H. W. (U., &amp; of Regensburg), N. H. (U. (2021). Shortcut Gestures for Mobile Text Editing on Fully Touch Sensitive Smartphones. https://doi.org/10.1145/3396233 University), B. E. (M., of Edinburgh), B. B. (U., University), M. C. (M., Data61), U. E. (C. S. I. R. O., of Toulouse), M. S. (I. R. I. T.- U., of Calgary), W. W. (U., University), A. P. (I. + M., Christoph Anthes (HIVE, U. of A. S. U. A., Dresden), W. B. (T. U., Khoury), C. D. (N. U., University), T. D. (M., of Applied Sciences, J. G. (C. U., Arts), Jason H. Haga (Digital Architecture Promotion Center, N. I. of A. I. S., Technology), Nurit Kirshenbaum (LAVA, U. of H. at M., Dylan Kobayashi (LAVA, U. of H. at M., University), T. L. (H., University), M. O. (T., … University), Y. Y. (H. (2021, May 1). Grand Challenges in Immersive Analytics. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3446866 Clarke, L., Hornecker, E., &amp; Ruthven, I. (2021, January 1). Fighting Fires and Powering Steam Locomotives: Distribution of Control and Its Role in Social Interaction at Tangible Interactive Museum Exhibits. Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445534]]></summary></entry></feed>